《虎胆龙威3》
炸弹处理组、特勤人员、州警
Helen, bomb squad, special services, state police
还有联邦调查局
and the FBI!
杰金森警官，你和紧急处理中心
Lieutenant Jergenson, you and Palmer,
到现场去防止人员留在街道上
I want you to go to St. John's emergency...
雷蒙，去找市政府工程处
in case we got any walk-ins from the street.
我必须有损害报告，非常重要
I got to find out a damage report. It's very important.
炸弹，有谁会想炸掉百货公司？
Bonwit Teller. Who the hell would want to blow up a department store?
你见过女人采购特价的鞋子吗？
Did you ever see a woman miss a shoe sale?
康妮，我要你开始查证名单
Connie, I want you to get started on a witness sheet.
瑞奇，你和乔要确定穿制服的
Ricky, you and Joe, you make sure the uniforms
在现场妥善的维护秩序
got it cordoned off there.
而且别让电视台的人到那去
And you don't let the damn TV crews in.
文森…
Benson!
督察…
Inspector, phone.
现在不行
Not now.
文森，你负责交通
Benson, traffic.
三点前清理完，否则又要大塞车
You get Fifth Avenue cleared up by 3:00 or we've got the traffic jam from hell!
华特，我想你最好接这通电话
Walter!I think you'd better take this.
重案组，柯督察
Major Case Unit. Inspector Cobb.
单纯的赛门去找蛋糕师傅 他说“给我你的派
Said Simple Simon to the pie man, going to the fair...
不然就敲你脑袋”
"Give me your pies or I'll cave your head in."
要了解，爆炸只是想引起注意
You see, Bonwits was just to make sure I had your attention.
请问麦克连刑警是否在那里？
Is there a detective named McClane there?
他在停职中
He's on suspension.
不，华特，他没有，今天没有
No, Walter, he's not. Not today.
你是那一位？
Who is this?
叫我赛门
Call me Simon.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我想要玩一场游戏
I want to play a game.
什么样的游戏？
What kind of game?
“赛门说”
"Simon Says."
赛门会告诉麦克连警官去做什么
Simon's going to tell Lieutenant McClane what to do...
而麦克连警官会听命行事
and Lieutenant McClane is going to do it.
不服从就要面对惩罚
Noncompliance will result in a penalty.
什么惩罚？
What penalty?
在公共场所的另外一声“轰”
Another big bang in a very public place.
你要麦克连警官去做什么？
What is it that you want Lieutenant McClane to do?
赛门说麦克连警官要去138街
Simon says Lieutenant McClane is to go to the corner of
和阿姆斯特丹街的转角口
138th Street und Amsterdam...
假如我没记错，应该是在哈林区
which is in Harlem if I'm not mistaken.
密瓦斯基，蓝柏
Kowalski! Lambert!
你们知道在那能找到麦克连吗？
You know where to find McClane?
说不定你能在教堂里找到他
Well, I kind of doubt you're gonna find him in church.
去看看他到底在干什么
Well, you better find out what rock he's under...
把他找来
and kick it over.
约翰
John.
谢了
Thanks.
多给两片
Give me two more.Come on.
老天，你看起来一塌糊涂
Jesus, John, you look like shit.
我们离开办公室时还剩什么案子
Where did we leave off with that roster?
红灯区有三起杀人事件已拖过夜
Well, we got three killings in Redhook the past two nights.
派麦伦去查
Put Miner on it.
还有吉纳迪，他说可能会来上班
And Genetti.The mayor's office will call before the day's out.
长岛有十四辆倾卸车失窃
Next, 14 dump trucks stolen from a yard in Staten Island.
十四辆？有人要开建设公司？
Fourteen. Jesus. What, somebody starting a construction company?
不，是约翰蓝利要清理他的公寓
No, that was John's landlady, going to clean his apartment.
是保险诈欺，在加州最容易办
Insurance fraud. That's a priority out in California.
承包商跟小偷一起分赃
The contractor splits the money with the thieves.
在纽泽西办过这种案子，记得吗？
We had that out in Jersey a couple of years ago, Joe. Remember?
看看凯利能怎么处理吧
See what Kelly can do with it.
昨晚乐透开什么号码？
Hey, what was the lottery number last night?
还是买警徽号码？瑞克
You still betting your badge, Rick?
对，每周都是买6991
Yeah. 6991, every week.
6991，幸运号码
6991. Lucky number.
全纽约的一半警察都是买警徽号码
Half the cops in New York play their badges.
孩子还好吗？
How are the kids, John?
听说还好
I hear they're okay.
你和荷莉说过话吗？
Did you talk with Holly?
我没有
No, I didn't talk to Holly.
到了，督察
Coming up on it, Inspector.
是这里面很热或只是因为我怕的要命？
Hot in here or am I just scared to death?
去确定枪贴好了
You want to make sure the gun's secure?
没问题
Yeah, it's good.
你知道，除了荷莉外
You know, you're the first woman
你是第一个看到我脱裤子的女人
since Holly who's seen me do this.
我很荣幸
I'm honored.
她也是
Yeah, so was she.
支援会在那里？
So where's the backup gonna be?
我们要往后撤到128街
We're gonna drop back to 128th Street.
什么？
What?
离十条街？你在开我玩笑
Ten blocks? Are you fuckin' kiddin' me?
噢！老天…这真好极了
Oh, man, that's just great.
华特，这究竟是怎么回事？
Well, hey, Walter, what is all this about, huh?
假如我不照做，那家伙说
If we don't do what this guy says,
他会再炸另一个公共场所
he's gonna blow up another public place.
但为什么是我？与我有什么关系
Well, why me? What does he got to do with me?
我不知道，他只说一定要你
I have no idea. He just said it had to be you.
被需要的感觉真好
Huh. It's nice to be needed.
约翰，荷莉…
Frankly, John...
华特，别再提荷莉的事行不行？
Hey, Walter, how about you mind your fuckin' business about Holly, huh?
你的任务和我的宿醉
You and Simon are fuckin' up a perfectly good hangover.
行了
Okay.
我们十五分钟后来接你
We'll be back to pick you up in 15 minutes.
慢慢来，我预期四分钟内会死
Take your time. I expect to be dead in four.
我们走，比利
Let's go, Billy.
叔叔
Hey, yo, Uncle!
来看看这个
Come look at this.
九点十分了，为何不在学校里？
It's ten after 9:00. Why aren't you in school?
东尼想卖这个给你
Tony wants to sell you this.
东尼？
Tony?
那个没脖子的老兄？
That no-neck dude they call Bad T?
他说他在垃圾堆找到这个
He says he found it in a Dumpster.
他老是偷别人东西
He keeps stealing from people,
有天某人会发现他倒在垃圾堆里
they're gonna find him in a Dumpster.
他没有偷
No, he didn't steal it.
他说是他叔叔送他的
He says his uncle gave it to him.
把那边的报纸给我
Mm-hmm. Hand me that newspaper over there.
别让别人利用你
Don't ever let people use you.
你拿着赃物在大街上走
You're running all over town with stolen property.
被抓到时
If you get caught,
你惹上麻烦，他只要否认就能脱身
you get in trouble...while he gets to deny the whole thing and walk away.
你是说你要我们拿回去给汤尼？
Y-You mean, you want us to take it back to Tony?
不是，我拿回去并告诉他
No, I'll take it back to Tony, with a message.
现在，你们要去那里？
Now, where you goin'?
去学校
School.
为什么？
Why?
去受教育
To get educated.
为什么？
Why?
好上大学
So we can go to college.
它为何那么重要？
And why is that important?
以便得到尊敬
To get 'espect.
受尊敬，谁是坏人？
Respect. Now, who's the bad guys?
卖毒品的人
Guys who sell drugs.
有枪的人
Guys who have guns.
谁是好人？
And who are the good guys?
我们是好人
We're the good guys.
谁会帮你？
Who's gonna help you?
没有人
Nobody.
那么谁会帮助你？
So who's gonna help us?
我们自己帮助自己
We're gonna help ourselves.
谁不会帮助我们？
And who do we not want to help us?
白人
White people.
没错
That's right.
快离开这，去上学
Now get on outta here. Go to school.
叔叔，你最好来看看这个
Uncle, you better come look at this.
看什么？
What?
因为有个白人站在街上
There's a white man standing in the street.
我曾经看过
I seen one.
不曾看过这样的
Not like this.
（我恨黑鬼）
去打911
Dial 911.
叫他们快点到这来
Tell the police to get up here quick.
有人快要送命了
Somebody's about to get killed.
你们上学去，听到了吗？
And get your butts to school, you hear me?
好了
All right.
早安
Morning.
Good morning.
你今天还愉快吗？先生？
You havin' a nice day, sir?
你感觉还好吗？
You feelin' all right?
我不想针对个人
Not to get too personal,
但一个白人站在哈林区中
but a white man standing in the middle of Harlem...
身上挂着我恨黑鬼的牌子
wearin' a sign that says "I hate niggers"...
若不是有强烈的个人诉求
has either got some serious personal issues
就是不顾死活了
or not all his dogs are barkin'.
我在对你讲话
Hey, I'm talkin' to you!
你在被那些人看见前还有十秒钟
Now you got about ten seconds before those guys see you.
万一他们看见了，就会杀你
And when they do, they will kill you.
懂吗？
You understand?
你快要有个糟糕的一天了
You are about to have a very bad day.
还用你说
Yeah, tell me about it.
先生，这是警察事务，为您的…
Sir, this is a police matter. For your own safety
这当然是警察的事，为你的安全
It's a police matter! For your own safety...
我建议你在警察到之前躲进我店
I suggest you hide your butt in my shop 'til the police get here.
搞什么？
What the fuck?
糟了
Aw, shit.
听我说，我是警察
Listen, I'm a cop.
什么？
What?
我正在办案，一小时有件爆炸案
I'm on a case. Somebody blew up Bonwit Teller's an hour ago.
你在收音机上听到了吗？
Did you hear about that on the news?
是同一个混球叫我这么做的
The same asshole who did that...
若我不做他就炸掉别的，懂吗？
said I got to come to Harlem and do this...or he's gonna blow up something else. Do you understand?
狗屎
Shit, shit, shit.
听着，我有枪，你该过街去
Listen, I got a gun.
他们有十把枪…
They got ten guns.
你该过街去
If you can get across the street, you should get across the street!
开始装疯，行吗？
Look, start acting crazy.
什么？
What?
像是个神经病，你知道吗？
All right? Like Looney Tunes. You know, like Bellevue.
宙斯，你的朋友吗？
Hey, Zeus, this a friend of yours?
他看起来像我的朋友吗？
He look like a friend of mine?
我想这小子刚从某医院偷跑出来
I think the dude just escaped from some hospital,
像是神经病院之类的
you know, like Bellevue.
我是…
I am the voice of my own god,
我自己的神
and my god...
我告诉图书管理员我的头很痛，但他不信
And I told the librarian that I had a bad headache, but she didn't believe me.
你们要相信，我的头真的很痛
I really do have a bad headache, though.
我的痛真的很痛，我感觉像…
I have a very bad headache! And my head does not feel...
去你的
Oh, man, shut the fuck up!
你犯了一个严重的错误
You've made a very bad mistake.
把那牌子弄掉
Cut that shit off!
把它弄掉
In your face, boy!
大伙，大伙
Fellas! Fellas!
这白小子恨黑鬼，我们该怎么办
Nature boy here hates niggers.Now what are we gonna do about that?
慢着，慢着
Hold up, hold up, hold up!
狗屎
Oh, shit!
退后！
Back!
退后
Back up!
宙斯，你是怎么回事？
Hey, hey, what you trippin' on?
退后！现在
Back the fuck up now!
走吧
Get outta here!
快点跑
Come on.
离开车子，下车
Grab the cab! Grab the goddamn cab!
别开枪
Don't shoot, huh? Don't shoot me!
站起来，快站起来
Get up! Come on! Get up!
退后，我不想用它但我会用它
Back up! I mean it! I don't want to, but I will!
你们晓得我会用它的
You know I will! Come on!
快点，走！走！走！
Drive! Drive! Drive!
走！走！走！
Go! Go!
快带我们离开这里，开车！
Go! Get the fuck outta here
开车，别停下来，闯红灯
Drive! Drive! Don't stop! Don't stop! Just keep drivin'! Run the red light! Drive, goddamn it!
拿去，我只有这么多
That's all I got!
把你的钱收起来，没人要你的钱
Put that fuckin' money away. Nobody's robbin' you, asshole.
他们会杀了你…
I'll fuckin' kill you.
狗屎
Shit!
闯红灯就对了，开车！
Just run all the lights! Drive.
别停下来
You got it, boss!
割的深吗？
That cut deep?
我怎么晓得？
How the hell would I know?
继续施压力
Just keep pressure on it.
妈的
Oh, fuck!
苏斯，对吧？我是约翰麦克连
Goddamn. Jesus, right? John McClane.
我欠你一份情
I owe you one.
你当然欠我一份情
Damn right you owe me!
你知道他们现在会怎么砸我的店？
You got any idea what those guys are doing to my shop right now?
冷静点
Chill out, Jesus.
冷静点？你想和我攀亲带故吗？
"Chill out"? Are you trying to relate to me?
别跟黑人装熟
Talk like a white man.
苏斯，对不起，我…
Look, Jesus, I'm sorry you got involved, all right?
你为何一直叫我苏斯？
Why do you keep calling me "Jesus"?
我看起来像波多黎哥人吗？
I look Puerto Rican to you?
刚才那些人叫你苏斯
Guy back there called you "Jesus," didn't he?
他们不是叫我苏斯，是宙斯
He didn't say, "Jesus." He said, "Hey, Zeus."
我的名字叫宙斯
My name is Zeus.
宙斯？
Zeus?
没错，宙斯，阿波罗的父亲
Yeah, Zeus! As in father of Apollo, Mount Olympus...
住在奥林帕斯，别惹我
Mount Olympus... Don't-fuck-with-me...
否则我用闪电劈你，我叫宙斯
Or-I'Il-shove-a-lightning-bolt-up-your-ass Zeus!
你有意见吗？
You got a problem with that?
不，我没意见
No. I don't have a problem with that.
市区，警察局
Downtown. Police plaza.
那真是太好了
Oh-ho. Oh, that's just great.
不管肤色，列出他逮过的每一个
Get a record of all his collars, recent releases...and list of anybody else he might have looked at sideways.
这是典型的自大狂，是一种病态
It's textbook megalomania. It's a pathological state...
他幻想能够主宰一切
in which fantasies of control or omnipotence predominate.
他想要控制他，他的行动、思想
He wants control over him. He wants control...
甚至他的情绪和感情
over his actions, over his thoughts, even his emotions.
听起来像是你有位神秘的仰慕者
Sounds like you got a secret admirer, John.
也许他会送花来给我
Yeah, maybe he'll send me some flowers.
大家都晓得你喜欢同性恋
Everybody knows you like pansies.
不是那种感情，这家伙很丑陋
It's not that kind of emotion. This guy is ugly.
他的情况如何？
How is that?
给他冲个澡就好了
Nothing wrong with him a shower wouldn't cure.
啤酒通常是喝到肚子里的，约翰
Beer is normally taken internally, John.
请给我几颗阿斯匹灵
Just give me some aspirins, will you?
我去拿，自己按住这
Yeah, okay. Hold this here.
这是佛列得谢勒，约翰，是…
This is Fred Schiller, John, and he's a...
是心理医师，我知道
A shrink. Yeah, I got it.
我们在应付的是黑夜般个性的人
Yes. I was saying that we're dealing with a megalomaniacal personality...
可能还有偏执狂…
with possible paranoid schizophrenia.
略过这一段，直接告诉我
Hey, hey, how about we just skip down to the part...
这与我有什么关系？
where you tell me what the fuck this has to do with me, huh?
我不知道
I don't know.
我所知道的是这家伙想要打击你
I mean, what I do know is it does have specifically to do with you.
要你随着他的节拍起舞，然后…
He wants you to dance to his tune and then...
叫我脱掉衣服让他搞？
Put on a dress and fuck me?
我本来要说，杀死你
I was going to say, "kill you."
他目前愤怒异常
He's sitting on an awful lot of rage...
在受到压力时，他必须发泄出来
and it could be manifested physically if he's stressed.
你逮捕的人？或是惹火过某人？
Somebody you arrested? Somebody you pissed off?
那名单可长了
Well, that could be one hell of a long list.
去你的，乔
Fuck you, Joe.
那种人不喜欢匿名行事
See, these people don't like to work anonymously.
他们要你知道是谁这样对你
They want you to know who's doing it to you.
所以赛门这个名字可能不是假名
So this name Simon is probably not an alias.
是真名或是相关性的
It's probably Simon or some variation.
赛门，罗勃E，86年被捕
Simon, Robert E. Busted in '86.
绑架案，判刑十到十五年
Extortion, kidnapping. Ten to fifteen.
服刑七年
Did seven years for good behavior...
两个月前因行为良好假释
released on a state work furlough two months ago.
穿穿看
Check it.
谢了，雷
Thanks, Rick.
巴伯赛门是个生意人
Bob Simons was a bankrupt businessman
他绑架了合伙人的女儿
who kidnapped his partner's daughter.
他是想不开而不是疯子
He's a fuck-up not a psycho.
我们要找的人是疯子
The guy we're looking for is nuts.
一个很懂炸弹的疯子
A nut who knows a lot about bombs.
我们在游乐场找到这个
We found this in a playground.
职业级的，很正点的东西
Professional.Very cool stuff.You know, boom.
可以这样摔来摔去的吗？查理
You think you should slam it around like that, Charlie?
尚未混合，不会有害
It's unmixed. You can't hurt it.
这玩意很先进，是两液型的
This stuff is cutting-edge. It's a binary liquid.
什么？
A what?
就像AB胶，有两种液体
Like epoxy. Two liquids.
其中任何单独一种…
Either one by itself...
什么都没有，但混合它们之后…
You got nothing. But mix 'em...
理奇
Ricky.
你为何要炸掉那张椅子
Charlie, you're gonna be wearin' that chair up your ass!
查理，你在干什么？
Christ Almighty, Charlie!
像我所做的，很正点的东西
Like I said, very cool stuff.
像这样的包装可以事先预警
Now, with a package like this, you get a warning.
这种炸弹要引爆必须解除保险
Now, the bomb has to arm itself.
你会看见红色液体在引爆之前
You'll see the red liquid pump
会先泵进透明液体中
into the clear before it detonates.
爆炸前有多少时间？
How long before?
十秒、两分钟，任何可能都有
Ten seconds. Two minutes. Could be anything.
一旦它们混合了
But once it's mixed, be somewhere else.
赶快逃命
This stuff has got to be pretty rare.
这玩意应该很罕见，能查出眉目
We ought to be able to find out if any of it's missing somewhere.
已经查到了
I already did.
利文渥实验室 周末时遭窃
Livermore Labs. Theft over the weekend.
足够能再做另一个？乔
Has he got enough to make another one, Joe?
约两千磅
About 2,000 pounds.
那种东西？
Of that?
引爆器可以用任何东西作成
Well, the detonating mechanism can be anything:
无线电、电子仪器
Radio, electrical.
你甚至能用呼叫器
Hell, you could use a beeper and phone it in.
督察…
Inspector! Inspector, it's him.
这一只炸弹有双重回路
He's got a double Alberti feedback loop on it.
相当难处理的小技巧，在黎巴嫩…
A nasty little trick I believe once used in Lebanon.
查理，查理！
Charlie. Charlie!
查理
Charlie, shh.
开始追踪
Want to start the trace?
赛门
Simon.
他拿着板子游街，但他仍存活着
He wore the board, walked the street and survived.
我的鸽子还好吗？
Hauptman Walter, where are my pigeons now?
鸽子？
"Pigeons"?
我有两只鸽子，一黑一白那天飞了
I had two pigeons, bright and gay, fly from me the other day.
他们为什么飞走，你并不知道
Why was it they did go? You cannot tell, you do not know.
你是说麦克连
You mean McClane?
不，我指的是圣诞老人
No, I mean Santa Claus.
我在这
Yeah, I'm here.
终于出现了，你的朋友呢？
Ah, there after all. And your friend?
卡特，我们在另外一间房需要你
Carver! Carver! Come on. We need you in the other room.
快点，走啊
Let's go! Come on.
他们需要你，去吧
They need you. Go.
他也在这
Yeah, he's here too.
我能和他谈谈吗？
And may I speak with him?
那位黑皮肤的撒马利亚人呢？
Well, is the ebony Samaritan there now?
你对黑皮肤有意见吗？
You got a problem with ebony?
没有，我动了些脑筋
No, no. My only problem is that I went to some
为麦克连准备了那场游戏
trouble preparing that game for McClane.
你干预了设计好的计划
You interfered with a well-laid plan.
你可以把那好计划塞进屁眼里
Yeah? Well, you can stick your well-laid plan up your well-laid ass.
别耍小聪明
That was not smart.
这牵涉到人命
There are lives at stake here.
时间不够，督察
Not enough time, Inspector.
你最好希望他会再打来
You better hope he calls back.
他会的
He will.
瑞奇，去叫外面的人声音小一点
Ricky, you want to tell those people to shut the hell up out there!
小声一点
Hey! Keep it down here!
赛门，他不代表我们全部
Simon. He wasn't speaking for all of us.
那很不愉快，别让它再发生
That was unpleasant. Don't let it happen again.
你叫什么名字？孩子
So, what's your name, boy?
别叫我孩子
Don't call me "boy"!
抱歉，只是想有幽默感一点
I'm sorry. It was a poor attempt at humor.
我本来想让你回家去了
I was going to send you home with a chiding...
但现在看起来…
but now I think perhaps
我们查到他了
you should join the game.
…你应该加入
We got him!
是在奥斯陆的公用电话
It's a pay phone in, in Oslo.
等一下，是墨西哥的佛瑞斯
No, w-wait, they say it's Juarez, Mexico.
不，现在他们说墨西哥的劳瑞斯
No, wait. No, wait. N-Now they're saying it's Juarez, Mexico.
算了，澳洲？他捣乱了整个系统
Forget it! Australia? He's scrambling up their system.
我们根本不知道他在那里
They don't know where he is.
和电话公司玩得愉快吧？
Having fun with the phone company, are we?
赛门说麦克连和那位先生
Simon says McClane and the Samaritan...
要去72街与百老汇交口地铁站
will go to the subway station at 72nd and Broadway.
我十五分后打去那边的公用电话
I will call you in 15 minutes on the pay phone outside the station.
不准有警察，没接电话就算失败
No police. Failure to answer will constitute noncompliance.
你懂吗？约翰
Do you understand me, John?
我懂，我晓得你是玩小孩的游戏
Oh, yes, I understand. I understand that you're a fuckin' whacko that likes to play kids' games.
差得远了
Hardly.
差得远？那么你是谁？我抓过的
"Hardly"? Well, then, who are you? Somebody I sent up?
你做了什么？扒手、小偷
What'd you do? Shoplifting? Purse-snatching?
男扮女装？究竟是什么？
Cross-dressing? What?
即使我连人带椅子的把你偷走
You c-c-couldn't catch me
你也抓不到我
if I stole your ch-chair with you in it.
连人带椅子？那真的很刺激
My ch-ch-ch-chair with me in it? Ooh! That's very exciting.
让我问你一个问题，混球
Let me ask you a question, bonehead.
你为何想要杀我？
Why are you trying to k-k-k-k-kill me?
约翰，冷静点
John, John, calm yourself.
你为何不到警察局来？
Huh? Why don't you come on down here to police plaza...
我们以男子汉的方式来解决它
and we'll figure this out like a couple of men, huh?
到这里来
So come on down here.
你是在开玩笑，假如想要杀你
If killing you was all I wanted...
你现在早已死透了
You'd be dead by now.
赛门，我很感谢你重视麦克连
Simon.I can appreciate your feelings for McClane.
但相信我，那个混球不值得
But, believe me, the jerk isn't worth it.
他在警局里得罪了太多人
He's stepped on so many toes in this department...
下个月的这个时候他就得站大门
by this time next month, he's gonna be a security guard.
他的妻子也不想和他有任何瓜葛
His own wife wants nothing to do with him...
他离真正的酒鬼只有两步之遥
and he's about two steps shy of becoming a full-blown alcoholic.
一步，一步之遥
One step. One step.
听我说，你听起来像个聪明人
Now listen to me. You sound like a real smart guy.
你想要什么？
What is it that you want?
你是在说钱吗？
Are you talking about money?
随便啦
Well, whatever, whatever.
要知道麦克连只不过是只臭虫
McClane is a toilet bug.
把他忘掉，从此愉快过一生
Now, what would it take just to forget him and live happily ever after?
你知道钱对我有如粪土
You know, money is shit to me.
即使把诺克斯堡的黄金全都给我
I would not give up McClane
我也不会放弃麦克连
for all the gold in your Fort Knox.
十五分后在72街地铁公用电话
72nd Street subway. Pay phone. 15 minutes.
麦克连和他那位朋友
McClane and the Samaritan.
若你们还有点能力就已找到皮箱
If you're competent in the least, you found the briefcase.
那你们就晓得我说的惩罚是什么
So you know what I mean by penalty.
谢谢你对我的信心，华特
I want to thank you for that vote of confidence, Walter.
我想至少可以试试
Well, I thought it was worth a try.
这家伙已经彻底疯了
This guy's a raving maniac.
就个案来说他已说得很清楚
Well, he couldn't be any clearer if you got it from a case history.
他已经给了你有关他的身份
He gave you clues to his identity.
他带德国口音，说你们的诺克斯堡
He spoke German, he called it "your Fort Knox"...
当麦克连激怒他时，他会变口吃
and he stammered when McClane pushed him.
你认为这家伙能用钱摆平吗？
Now, you believe this guy really can't be bought?
不可能，提到钱反而会激怒他
There's no chance. And the very mention of money only enraged him further.
那是什么？
What's that?
你的警徽
It's your shield.
你又再要我当警察了？
Are you asking me to be a cop again, Walter?
瑞奇，去把他的枪找来给他
Ricky, get him his gun...
你还没有回答我的问题
You didn't answer my question.
你晓得是…
Joe, this time they...
嗨！
Hey!
你没回答我的问题，华特
You didn't answer my question, Walter.
是的，警官
Are you done, Lieutenant?
若你想准时到72街就得出发了
Now you two better get going if you're gonna get up to 72nd Street on time.
乔，这一次要给他们后援
Joe, this time they go with backup!
没问题
You got it!
我那里都不去
Whoa, whoa, whoa! I'm not going anywhere.
赛门说你必须得去
Simon says you gotta go!
我才不会为了神经病而自投罗网
I'm not jumping through hoops for some psycho!
那是白人与白人问题，你去处理
That's a white man with white problems. You deal with him.
当他过了110街以后再找我
Call me when he crosses 110th Street.
你为何要救我？
Hey. Why'd you save my ass?
我没有
I didn't.
我阻止白人警察在哈林区被杀
I stopped a white cop from gettin' killed in Harlem.
今天有一名白人警察被杀
One white cop gets killed today,
明天就会有上千个白人警察跟进
tomorrow we got a thousand white cops...
每一个都想藉机开枪，懂吗？
all of 'em with itchy trigger fingers. Got it?
把他弄回来
Get him back.
查理，你在那找到那颗炸弹的？
Charlie, where'd you find that bomb?
唐人街
Chinatown.
狗屎
Shit.
什么事？
Zeus! Yo, partner!
等等
Wait up!
我不是你的搭挡
Hey, hey, I ain't your partner.
我不是你的邻居或朋友
I ain't your neighbor, your brother or your friend.
我是位完全的陌生人
I'm your total stranger.
好，陌生人，你晓得在115街
Okay, stranger. Know where that park is at 115th Street
和圣尼克拉街的公园吗？
and St. Nicholas?
知道，在哈林区
Yeah, that's in Harlem.
你以为我们在那找到那颗炸弹的
Where do you think we found that bomb?
听我说，那家伙不在乎肤色
Listen, this guy doesn't care about skin color,
你在乎也没有用
even if you do.
我在干什么？
What am I doing?
振作点，有可能会更糟
Cheer up. Things could be worse.
有段时间我当夜班
I was working on a nice, fat suspension...
除了抽烟之外无所事事
smoking cigarettes and watching Captain Kangaroo.
他们到了电话那，但有个问题
Okay, they made it to the phone, but there's a problem.
什么意思？那问题有多大？
Well, what do you mean? How big a problem?
约三百磅重
Oh, about 300 pounds.
抱歉，警察事务需要用这座电话
Excuse me,We need this phone for official police business.
你们不介意吧？
Do you mind?
女士，我是警察，需要这具电话
Honey, I'm a cop. I need the phone right now.
闭嘴快滚，这是警察事务
Get off the damn phone, lady! Police business!
从来没遇见过
Well, I never!
我已经习惯这种事了
I can get used to this.
我相信你在对街能找到电话
I'm sure you can find a phone across the street, ma'am.
我们把话说清楚，我才是警察
Let's get something straight. I'm the only one here on official police business.
再也别做那种事
Don't ever do that shit again.
让我把话说清楚
Let's get something else straight.
你们需要我甚于我需要你们
You need me a lot more than I need you.
若你不喜欢我办事的方法
You don't like the way I do things?
很好，我不干了
Fine. I quit.
好了，我需要你
好，我需要你甚于你需要我
All right, I need you more than you need me.
哈罗
Hello.
相同羽毛共同飞 猪与下人皆一样
Birds of a feather flock together, so do pigs and swine.
蛇鼠之辈能尝试 我也将有我机会
Rats and mice have their chance as will I have mine.
很好，还押韵
Nice. It rhymes.
电话为何占线中？你们打给谁？
Why was the phone busy? Who were you calling?
神经病专线
The Psychic Hot Line.
我建议你正经点
I'd advise you to take this more seriously.
这是公共电话，你要我怎么说
Look, it's a public phone! What do you want me to say?
你可以直说有个胖女人在用电话
You can simply say there was a fat woman on it,
花了你们一点时间才让她离开
and it took you a minute to get her off!
约翰，你旁边垃圾筒内有炸药
Now, John, there's a significant amount of explosive in the trash receptacle next to you.
想跑的话它就会立刻爆炸
Try to run and it goes up now.
没有人会跑，但这里有上百人
Uh, nobody's gonna run, but I got a hundred people out here.
那正是我的意图
That's the point.
注意，问题来了
Now, do I have your attention?
我去圣爱弗时遇到一个男人
As I was going to St. Ives,
他有七位太太
I met a man with seven wives.
每位太太有七个麻袋
Every wife had seven sacks,
每个麻袋有七头猫
every sack had seven cats,
每头猫生了七只小猫
every cat had seven kittens.
小猫、猫、袋子、太太…
Kittens, cats, sacks and wives.
有几个人要去圣爱弗？
How many were going to St. Ives?
我的电话号码是555…
My phone number is 555...
不，我没完全听清楚，再说一次
No, no, no, wait! I didn't get all that! Say it again!
不可能，我的电话是555
Not a chance. My phone number is 555...
再加上答案，三十秒打电话给我
and the answer. Call me in 30 seconds
否则就得死
or die.
七个人有七个太太…
All right, seven guys with seven wives is...
闭嘴，麦克连，这方面我很行
Shut up, McClane. I'm good at this.
七个人有七个太太…
Seven guys and seven wives...
闭嘴，麦克连
Shut the fuck up, McClane!
他说七位太太各有七个袋子
He said seven wives with seven sacks.
七乘七是四十九，告诉我剩下的
Seven times seven is 49. Now tell me the rest.
七个袋子…
Uh, a sack with s-seven, seven, seven...
你有在听吗？
Weren't you listening?
你有什么问题？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我因宿醉而头痛的厉害
Well,Besides having a bad fuckin' hangover, for one thing!
好吧，49再乘每个袋子7只猫
All right, all right, all right! Seven wives times seven, 49.
7乘49是343，对吧？
With seven cats... Seven times 49 is 343, right?
是的，是你告诉我的
What, are you asking me or telling me?
是我说的，7乘343是…
I'm telling you. 343 times seven is...
2401，你算出来也一样吧？
One, zero, 24.2,401. That's what you got, right?
是，就是那样？5552401
That's it. Dial. 555-2401.
不，等一下，是脑筋急转弯
No, wait, wait! It's a trick!
此话怎讲？
What do you mean?
我忘了那个男人
I forgot about the man.
什么男人？去他的，还有十秒…
What man? Fuck the man! We got ten seconds here!
他说有几个人要去圣爱弗，对吧
He said how many were going to St. Ives, right?
谜语一开始说一个男的有七位太太
The riddle begins, "As I was going to St. Ives, I met a man with seven wives."
那个人和他的太太那都不去
The guy and his wives aren't going anywhere.
那他们要去那？
What are they doing?
坐在大路旁等，我怎么会知道？
Sittin' in the fuckin' road, waitin' on the moon! How the hell should I know, McClane!
那谁要去圣爱弗？
Well, who was going to St. Ives then?
那个人，只有那一个人
The guy. Just the guy.
只有一个人
Just one guy?
答案是一个人
The answer's one.
你怎么拨1？
Just one guy. How do you dial "one"?
555-0001
555-0001.
只有一个人要去
0001. Just one guy's goin'.
哈罗，约翰
Hello, John.
小事一椿，下次出个难一点的吧
Yeah, a piece of cake. Give us something harder next time.
但是你们慢了十秒
But you're ten seconds late.
不，答案是一
No, no! The answer is one!
垃圾筒里有炸弹！
There's a bomb in the trash can!
大家快趴下！
Everybody get down!
有炸弹…
There's a bomb!
趴下…
Get down!
欢迎到纽约
Welcome to New York.
好了，起来吧，我们走
Here. You can have it. Come on. Come on. Let's go.
炸弹
A bomb.
我没有说“赛门说”
I didn't say, "Simon says."
现在九点五十了，约翰
It's 9:50, John.
三号地铁正抵达那边
The Number Three train is arriving now.
我在那列火车上留了点东西
I left something provocative on that train, John.
赛门说在十点二十分之前到新密尔瓦基街
Simon says get to the pay phone next to the news kiosk...
和华尔街地铁站
in Wall Street Station by 10:20...
去接公用电话，否则三号列车升天
Or the Number Three train and its passengers vaporize.
除了民用交通工具外用别的
Use any means of travel other than civilian
我就炸火车
I blow the train.
想疏散乘客我就炸火车
Attempt to evacuate the subway, I blow the train.
我三十分后打给你们，要到哦！
I call you in 30 minutes. Be there.
完了
We're fucked.
以纽约的交通 三十分内走完九十条街？
90 blocks in 30 minutes in New York traffic?
有可能要两倍的时间
It could be double that.
我们甚至连车都没
We don't even have a car.
先生，我是警察，因公务徵用车
Hey! Sir! I'm a cop.I am requisitioning this car for official police business!
你在干什么？你快下来
What the fuck are you doing? My cab!
上车
Get in! Get in!
我以前开过计程车，最快的是…
Listen, I used to drive a cab. The fastest way south is...
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
你说什么？
What were you saying?
我说我以前开过计程车
I was saying, I used to drive a cab...
要去第九大道最快方法是往南走
and Ninth Avenue is the fastest way south.
但我们似乎在向东走
But we seem to be going east.
你在干嘛？麦克连，我说过最…
Where the hell are you going, McClane? I told you Ninth Avenue...
别吼了，我知道我在干什么
Stop with the goddamn yelling! I know what I'm doing!
连上帝都不知道你在干什么
Not even God knows what you're doing!
他们向东自72街往公园走
They're headed east on 72nd towards the park.
华尔街在南边
But Wall Street is south!
别再对我吼，我头痛的要命
Man, stop yelling at me! I got a bad headache.
向南走最快的方法不是第九大道
And the best way south is not Ninth Avenue.
而是穿越公园
It's through the park.
噢！老天
Oh, dear.
我告诉过你公园路总是堵车
I told you the Park Drive was always jammed.
我没说走公园路
I didn't say Park Drive.
我说的是穿越公园
I said, "through the park."
狗屎，我们追丢了，他们往南走
Shit! We lost them. They're in the park, headed south.
让开
Get outta here!
疯子
Crazy prick!
我发现他们了，康妮，在公园内
I got him, Connie. He's taking the scenic route.
让开
Outta the way!
Look out! Get outta there!
小心！小心！你是朝那些人开过去？
Watch it! Watch out! Are you aiming for these people?
不是
No!
也许有想过
Maybe that mime.
树！树！
Tree! Tree! Tree! Haul!
这里是怎么回事？
What's going on here?
小心！
Look out! Whoa!
树！树！
Tree! Tree!
坐稳了
Just hang on.
石头！石头！
Broads! Rock, rock!
麦克连！小心！
Hey, look out down there!
麦克连…
McClane!
让开
Outta the way.
天主教徒是怎么做的？
How do Catholics do that thing?
先由上往下，再向右再向左
North, south, west, east.
什么时间了
How much time?
27分了
Twenty-seven minutes.
帅！72街到百老汇才三分钟
Ha! 72nd and Broadway...to Central Park South in three minutes!
这一定是记录
That's gotta be a fuckin' record!
现在怎么办？
Yeah. Now what?
我们需要一辆救火车
Yeah, we need a fire truck.
什么？
What?
跟在后面
To follow.
- 911专线 - 我是约翰麦克连警官
- 911. - Lieutenant John McClane, NYPD...
警徽号码7479
access number 7479,
要你们立刻派救护车来
calling from a civilian transmitter.
好，稍候一下
Get me an emergency dispatcher right away!
有两位警员在14街第九大道口
I got two officers down at the corner of 14th Street and Ninth Avenue!
负伤倒地，急需救护车
Need an ambulance! Over!
他们会送往河边医院
Most of the calls on the west side go to Roosevelt Hospital.
距我们要去的地方只有两条街远
That's two blocks from here.
他妈的，慢一点，麦克连
Slow the fuck down, McClane!
和美式足球一样，对吧？
Kind of like football, isn't it?
什么？
What?
前面有人替你开路你直奔得分区
Get yourself a blocker and head for the end zone.
如果你报华尔街 我们就可以一直跟着它
If you'd said Wall Street, we could have followed him all the way.
错了，第十四街有另外一家医院
Wrong. South of 14th Street's a different hospital.
圣路克医院 坐稳了
Saint Luke's. Hang on.
时间呢？
Time?
10:02，十八分钟了，还有一半的路
10:02. We're halfway there with 18 minutes to go.
去他的，坐稳了
Fuck this. Hang on.
坐稳
Hang on. Hang on! Hang on!
换你开车
Slide over and take the wheel!
你要去那？
Where you goin'?
我要先上那列火车去找
We should be ahead of that train, right?
你不能上那列火车
No, you're not gonna...get on that train!
我要上那列火车
I'm gonna get on that train!
你十点二十前要赶到那公用电话
You gotta get to that pay phone by 10:20.
你要干什么？
What are you gonna do?
我要去找那个炸弹
I'm gonna get that bomb!
听我说，你失败了我掩护你
Listen, you fail, I cover your ass.
我失败了你掩护我
I fail, you cover my ass.
若我们俩都失败了？
And if we both fail?
那就玩完了
Then we're both fucked.
快走，十点二十前到那公用电话
Go, now! Drive! Get to that phone booth by 10:20! Go!
真是我的幸运日
My lucky fuckin' day.
该死
Shit.
看路
Look out!
让开…让开
Get outta the way!
这是个坏主意
This is a bad idea!
借过，借过，请让路
Excuse me! Excuse me! Just get outta the way, please.
华尔街112号
112 Wall Street.
等一下
Wait,
这不是计程车，你不懂
this isn't a taxi. You don't understand.
你的空车灯亮着的
Your light's on.
我把话说明白，华尔街112号
I'll make it simple. 112 Wall Street,
否则我就让你吊牌
or I'll have your medallion suspended.
怎么？你不喜欢白人？
What? You don't like white people?
华尔街112号，没问题
112 Wall Street. You got it.
把脚抬起来，别碍事
Move your legs here. Get your legs outta the way!
抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
狗屎
Shit!
借过，先生，借过
Excuse me, sir. Pardon me, please. Excuse...
请让开可以吗？
Will you step outta here for a minute?
什么？
What?
我是警察，请让开
I'm a cop. Step outta here for a minute, please.
借过，请让路
Excuse me, please! Can I get through here, please?
借过
Excuse me!
Excuse me, please.
打扰，先生，我在等电话
Excuse me, sir, but I'm expecting a call.
我需要那具电话
I need that phone.
你为何不用另外一支？
Why don't you use the other phone?
先生，拜托，我需要那具电话
Sir, please. I need to use that phone.
听着，兄弟，是我先到的
Hey, listen, bro, I was here first.
兄弟？
"Bro"?
离那电话远一点
Get away from the goddamn phone!
把手举起来
Get your hands up!
我必须接这通电话
I have to answer that phone.
闭嘴，把手举在空中
Just shut up and get 'em in the air!
小心，抱歉，借过，小心
Watch it! Excuse me! Pardon me! Watch it. Watch your back. Watch it.
各位，我是纽约市警察
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm a New York police officer.
我要你们冷静的朝车那一端移动
I'm gonna ask you to calmly and quietly start moving towards the other end of the car.
请现在就走
Go now, please. Go now. Fuck!
快走，小心
Go! Hurry! Watch out!
小心，小心…快走
Watch. Watch it. Go!
我必须接那通电话
I have to answer that phone.
把手举高
Get 'em up!
听着，你若要开枪就请便
Look, if you have to shoot me...then you go ahead and you shoot me!
但我必须接这通电话，行吗？
But I have to answer this phone! All right?
我在这里
I'm here.
麦克连呢？
And McClane?
他在路上，他太胖了体能不好
He's on his way. You know, he's a little slow. He's kind of out of shape.
我要求的是你们两个
The rules applied to both of you.
恐怕这与我的要求不符，再见
I'm afraid this is noncompliance. Good-bye.
相信我，各位
Trust me, guys.
趴下来
Duck.
快离开那，趴下
Hey, get outta there! Get outta there! Duck, asshole!
麦克连？
McClane?
什么？
What?
可以直接看到地铁
You can see right down into the subway.
来了几辆消防车？
How many fire trucks you count?
安静，安静
You guys, you guys.
从那里怎么看的清楚？
How can you see from up there?
到下面去
Damn. Get in there.
警员，叫那些人退后，行吗？
Officer, tell those people to get the hell back, will you?
一大堆人轻伤，几个脑震荡
We got a shitload of cuts and bruises, a couple concussions...
几个老人心律器停了
some old guy's pacemaker stopped
还有一位孕妇羊水破了
and a pregnant girl's water broke, and that's all.
你的情况如何？约翰
How you doin', John?
还好
Still can't hear too good.
你还活着是个奇迹
Well, it's a miracle you're still alive.
问题就出在那了，乔
Yeah, that's the problem, Joe.
什么？
What?
奇迹的部份
The miracle part.
我们能准时到这的机会有多少？
What are the odds of us making it down here on time?
零
Hmm. Zip.
那颗炸弹无论如何都会爆炸
That bomb was gonna go off no matter what.
他想要它在这里爆炸
He wanted it to go off right down here.
把这玩意拿掉，大卫
Take this off me, Dave.
这地方为何那么特别？
Well, what's so special about this place?
我不知道，事情拼凑不起来
I don't know. Something just doesn't add up.
麦克连警官？
Lieutenant McClane?
他们要找你和卡特先生
They're asking for you and a Mr.Carver.
在那？
Where?
约翰
John.
约翰，这位是安迪克罗斯
John, this is Andy Cross
他是联邦调查局的
with the FBI.
这位是查尔斯先生，他是…
This is Bill Jarvis. He's, uh...
我是另一个单位的
I'm, uh, with another agency.
幸会
It's good to meet you.
这是麦克连警官和卡特先生
This is Lieutenant McClane. This is Mr.Carver.
我们先要问几个问题
Uh, we got a couple questions first.
认识这个人吗？
You recognize this guy?
不认识
No.
这一个呢？
How about this one?
你呢？
How about you?
你认得出电话上的声音吗？
Did you recognize the voice on the phone?
是否注意到有车子在跟踪你？
Have you, uh, noticed any cars following you around?
没有
No.
有任何人跟踪你吗？任何监视？
Anybody following you at all? Any kind of surveillance?
电话、屋子，任何不寻常的事？
Telephone? House? Anything unusual at all?
你既然提到了，我的脚趾间烧痛
Well, now that you mention it...I have experienced a,
我以为是香港脚之类的
you know, like a burning sensation between my toes.
你在虚应委蛇，他们说你会合作
We read your jacket, Lieutenant. We were told you would be cooperative.
合作什么？
Cooperate with what?
等一下
Hey, now, wait a minute.
这些家伙在浪费时间
We're just wasting time here in this goddamn van.
你们想分享情报，回馈一些如何
You want to share...information, how about sending a little our way as well?
我们想先听听他知道什么
Look, we want to hear what he knows first.
你们让我们看了照片…
You give us pictures, and then...
我们想知道他知道些什么
Look, we want to hear...what he knows first.
我们知道的和你们一样，行吗？
Hey, I know as much as you know, all right?
有个家伙在外面到处放炸弹
There's a guy out there settin' off bombs.
他自称叫赛门，说话带德国口音
He calls himself Simon. He speaks with a German accent.
不知为什么他十分生我的气
And, for some reason, he's very angry with me.
也许你们能告诉我是为什么
Now maybe you can tell me why, fellas, huh?
第一个人叫法瑞斯塔戈
The first man there is Matthias Targo:
前匈牙利陆军，爆破专家
Was Hungarian Army, explosives expert.
我们相信现在是为乌克兰人工作
Now we believe he's working for the Iranians.
工作？
"Working"?
自主的恐怖份子，受雇于合约
Freelance terrorism, by contract.
那个女的是谁？
Who's the girl?
他的爱人
Targo's other half.
谣传有人在他们床单下摆了炸弹
Rumor is the Israelis slipped a bomb in between their sheets.
那天他不在家，也许炸死了她
Uh, he wasn't at home, but they think maybe they got her.
第二个人是前东德上校安全官
Second man was an obscure colonel in the East German Army.
负责渗透部队，像坦克大决战中…
He ran an infiltration unit; the kind of thing
纳粹德军所做的，派说英文的部队
the Nazis did at the Battle of the Bulge.English-speaking troops...
我看过那部电影
Yeah, yeah, l-I saw the movie.
医药记录显示他饱受头痛之苦
All we know of him is GDR medical records show he suffers from migraines.
他的名字叫彼得克里格
His name is Peter Krieg.
很卓越的简报，各位
Well, that is an exceptional report, fellas.
现在你们要告诉我 这到底与我何干吗？
Now do you want to tell me what the hell this has to do with me?
鲁伯这个姓对你有意义吗？警官
The name Gruber mean anything to you, Lieutenant?
有印象
It rings a bell, yeah.
洛杉矶，在洛杉矶大楼的那一次
L.A. That thing in the building in L.A.
彼得克里格的原名是赛门彼得鲁伯
Peter Krieg was born Simon Peter Gruber.
他是汉斯鲁伯的哥哥
He's Hans Gruber's brother.
是的，洛城的那件事
Yeah, it's that thing in L.A.
我们觉得他会尽一切置你于死地
We figure he's got you fitted up for a toe tag and he's gonna do anything to get it tied.
督察，是他
Inspector! Inspector, it's him.
别让他知道我们在这
Don't let him know we're here.
赛门
Simon.
不晓得车里联邦调查局的人是谁
Inspector. Now, who from the FBI is in the van, I wonder?
想想看，一定有克罗斯
Let's see, almost certainly Cross.
说吧，安德鲁，说哈罗啊
Come on, Andrew, say hello.
哈罗
Hello.
我知道你从不单枪匹马
And I know you never run alone.
所以打个招呼吧，比尔
So say hello, Bill.
还是咬眼镜来消除紧张？
Still trying to butch up by chewing on your glasses, huh?
这位先生老是让事情复杂化
This, gentlemen, as they say, is where the plot thickens.
我在纽约的1446所学校中
I have put 2,400 pounds of explosive
放了具两千四百磅的炸弹
in one of the 1,446 schools in greater New York.
定时器设定在下午三点爆炸
It is fitted with a timer set to explode at exactly 3:00 p.m.
谢谢，我假定你们的沉默表示已了解了
Thank you. Your silence says I'm understood.
你说是两千四百磅？
Did you say 2,400 pounds?
是的，请别再打岔
Yes, but please don't interrupt again!
赛门说你们若要疏散学校
Simon says if you attempt to evacuate schools...
那么炸弹会经无线电引爆
the bomb will be detonated by radio.
各位，会有人在监视的
And, gentlemen, someone will be watching.
下午三点 会有一所学校永久消失
Repeat: One school will be dismissed at 3:00 p.m.,
除非…
permanently, unless...
除非什么？
Unless what?
除非约翰麦克连和他的新朋友
Unless John McClane and his new best friend...
能完成我为他们所设定的目标
complete the tasks I set them.
约翰，你在听吗？
John, are you listening?
是
Yeah.
在汤金广场后面有座公用电话
The pay phone beyond Hope Thompkins Square Park.
二十分钟，用走的，不必赶
Twenty minutes. Go by foot. No rush.
若你真的聪明
If you're really clever,
你就能知道学校炸弹的位置和密码
you'll learn the location of the bomb and the code to disarm it.
另外，我们买到便宜的引爆器
Oh, and by the way, gentlemen, we got something of a bargain on radio detonators.
问题是警用及FBI频率会引爆
The only problem is, the darn things seem to respond to police and FBI frequencies...
所以假如换成我 我就不会用无线电
so if I were you, I'd keep off your radios.
赛门，等一下
Simon, wait.
两千四百磅那液体炸弹，老天
2,400 pounds of that liquid stuff.
替我接局长
My God! Get me the commissioner.
他在开记者招待会，半小时会到
He's doing a press conference. He's supposed to be here in half an hour.
好吧，瑞奇，集合现场资深警员
All right, Ricky, get every senior officer on the site. Get 'em here right away.
别跟我来那套管辖权的狗屁
You're not gonna give me any jurisdictional nonsense on this?
我有两个孩子在64街的学校里
I got two kids in the school on 64th Street.
- 我怎么帮忙？- 你有多少人？
- What can I do to help you? - How many men have you got?
75人，但紧急求援的话
Seventy-five, but if I push the panic button,
能从华府调五百人来
I can get 500 from Washington.
什么时候到？
When?
两点半到三点之间
2:30, 3:00.
到那个时间前…
Between now and then?
我们得独自做这件事，我们走
We're gonna have to do this all by ourselves. Let's go.
汤金广场在两里外，你们得走了
Now, Thompkins Square Park is more than two miles away, so you guys better get running.
别用无线电，带着我的电话
No radios. You take my telephone.
有任何事，利用报案中心交换机
You get anything, you call me through the switchboard.
祝好运
Good luck.
谢谢，去找到那颗炸弹
Thanks. Find that bomb.
瑞奇，他们在那？
Ricky, where are they?
在这边
Right over here.
最资深的是艾伦队长
Senior man present is Chief Allen.
那个单位？
Chief of what?
交通
Transit.
好，谢谢，瑞奇
Okay, thanks, Ricky. Gentlemen,
各位，我们有个决定要下
we have a decision to make.
造成这件事的人说他另外安置了
Chief Allen, the man who has done this has told us that
一个很大的炸弹 就在纽约的某个学校里
he has planted another very large bomb in a school here in the New York area.
他说我们不能疏散
And he has told us that we cannot evacuate.
但他没说我们不能搜索
But he has not said that we cannot search.
我建议我们动员每个人
Now, I recommend we get everybody,
而且我指的是每一个公务员
and I mean everybody...
不论是警察、交通、消防
I'm talking about police, transit, sanitation, fire,
甚至图书馆的人
even the goddamn librarians...
我们开始搜索，从现在开始
and we start searching schools, and I mean right now.
我说的是市内的数千幢建筑物
I'm talking about a thousand buildings within the city limits.
我们只有三小时五十分去完成
And we have three hours and 15 minutes to do it in.
我们要设法尽量不让媒体知道
Now, I'd like to keep the media out of this as long as possible...
因为他们一涉及就会造成恐慌
because if they get in, we've got a panic.
我们大家同意吗？
Are we in agreement?
好了，大伙们，我们走
All right, come on, guys! Let's go!
他们相信了
They bought it.
我们可以开始了
You can begin.
筹备、安排…
Hook, line...
完全成功
and sinker.
我们走！我们走！
All right now, men, let's go! Let's go!
特利巡佐！
Sergeant Turley!
特利巡佐，过去五分钟线路爆满
In the last five minutes, the volume of calls in here has tripled.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell is goin' on?
停一下，让我解释一下
Stop! Let me explain.
今天剩下的时间里
For the rest of the day,
我们要负责处理局里的通信
we're supposed to handle the department's communications.
此话怎讲？
What do you mean, "handle"?
他们关闭无线电，电话通通来此
They're shutting down the police band. All calls will be coming through this switchboard.
那我就要嫁给唐诺川普了
And I'm gonna marry Donald Trump.
巴伯，怎么回事？
Walsh, what's going on?
为何大家都撤离这里了？
Why'd everybody tear out of here?
潘蜜拉，看看你的表，要换班了
Come on, Pamela, look at your watch. It's comin' up on shift change.
局长担心加班费的事
The bean counters are worried about overtime...
所以我们让大家回局里打卡下班
so we sent everybody back to the precinct to punch out.
下一班随时会到
The next shift is gonna be here in a minute.
你们是满口胡说八道
You are so full of shit, Walsh!
谢谢
Thank you.
搞什么鬼？
What the hell...
谢谢，巴伯塔克，工程处的
Detective. Bob Thompson, City Engineer's Office.
我们要去处理损害的部份
We'd like to get an idea of the damage.
你们来的可真快
Man, you guys really got here fast.
这里是华尔街，有许多钱
Well, it's Wall Street, sir. Lot of money here.
有许多意见很多的人
Lot of opinion makers
市长不想得罪他们，你知道吧
the mayor doesn't want to piss off, you know?
就是这里了？
This is it?
我的老天，有人玩得很愉快
Holy Toledo! Somebody had fun.
若你能替我的同事带路我很感谢
I'd appreciate it if you'd show my associates the way down.
没问题
Yeah, yeah, sure.
吉米，有手电筒吗？墨菲你也来
Jimmy! You got the flashlight? Murphy! Come on! You too!
瑞克华许
Rick Walsh.
约翰康屈
John Cochran.
走，各位，我们走
Come on, gentlemen. Let's go.
你们可能也处理世贸中心案
You were probably at the World Trades.
你们晓得那是什么情况
You know what that mess was.
请通知李先生说范登先生来了
Please inform Mr.Little that Mr.Vanderfloog is here.
范登先生是吗？
Mr.Vanderfloog?
有位范登先生找李先生
There's a Mr.Vanderfloog for Mr.Little.
往下二十米
Go down 20 meters! Come on!
下面的蒸汽不少
Lot of steam down here.
炸断不少蒸汽管，像桑拿一样
Yeah,we snapped a couple of the steam pipes.It's like a sauna.
我们叫地铁的人关闭三号轨道
We got the subway guys to shut down the third rail.
紧急照明？
Some emergency lights?
是，用紧急照明，所以仍有光…
Yeah, emergency lights, and there's still some light...
别开枪
No shooting!
[德语]
说英文
Speak English!
我不认为阿道会说英文，对吧？
Otto doesn't speak English, do you, Otto?
我们是去那找来的这个人？
Where the hell did we get this guy?
那是塔戈的人
He's one of Targo's thugs.
一直往前开
Come on, come on. Pull all the way up.
洛城是什么事？你很有名？
So what was up with this L.A. Thing? You famous or something?
大概有名了五分钟
Yeah, for about five minutes.
别告诉我，你打黑人对吧？
Don't tell me. Rodney King, right?
去你的
Fuck you.
你知道我们说的那位赛门吗？
You know this guy Simon we're talking to?
我在洛城将他弟弟自32楼摔下
I threw his little brother off the 32nd floor of Nakatomi Towers out in L.A.
我想他对那件事有点生气
I guess he's a little pissed off about it.
等一下，你是在告诉我
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me I'm in this shit...
因为某白人警察把某白人混球弟弟
'cause some white cop threw
自屋顶扔下来 然后我在这受罪？
some white asshole's brother off a roof?
范登先生，企业关系部，我姓李
Mr.Vanderfloog? Felix Little, Corporate Relations.
抱歉让你久等
Sorry you had to wait,
但因地铁爆炸
but apparently there was an explosion in the subway.
造成我们警铃失灵
It's played hell with our alarms, I'm afraid.
我希望没出任何问题？
I trust there's nothing wron
不会的，一切安全无恙
Oh, no. Good lord, no. Safe and secure.
你在考虑货币汇兑的事
Now you were concerned about a currency exchange.
我们并不是一般的商业银行
Uh, we are not a commercial bank in the normal sense.
我们主要是政府的中央银行
We're primarily, governments, central banks, that sort of thing.
财政部是主要客户
Apart from the depository, of course.
当然
Of course.
你是从事花卉生意，范登先生
And you are in the flower business, Mr.Vanderfloog?
不，范登先生，那是金库的电梯
Oh, no, Mr.Vanderfloog, that's the vault elevator.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
我们的警铃感应声音与振动
it's against... Our alarms are sonic and seismic...
因为爆炸造成警铃失效
two things, which, I'm afraid, do not react well to explosions.
地铁系统和警铃不太协调
You know, this, this subway business has knocked all our systems into a cocked hat.
事实上我们必须拔掉它的插头
In fact, we've had to give up and pull the plug on the whole thing.
楼下现在只有少数几个人
The repair people are downstairs now.
老天
Good lord!
是的
Yes, yes.
天啊，如果谁知道了…
Heavens to Betsy! If anyone knew!
但…我以为这是货币汇兑
But I thought this was a currency exchange.
我想我们还是直接提款
Oh, I think we go straight to the withdrawal.
（美国联邦银行）
队长，你下来看看
Hey, Captain, you want to come down here...
有点不对劲
and take a look at this? Something's going on.
你认为如何？贾斯，能修好吗？
What do you think, guys? Will you be able to fix that?
只要再几分钟
Just a minute now.
好了，我马上回来
Okay, I'll be right back.
趴下
Down!
退后
Stay back!
快点啊！快点
Come on! Come on! Shit.
服务台
Ah, front desk.
快点下来，我遭到攻击了
Get your ass down here right now! I'm under attack!
放轻松点，也许你能活过此事
Hey, just relax, mate. Maybe you'll live through this.
狗屎
Shit!
我想他已经死了，亲爱的
I think he's dead, my dear.
伙计们上工吧
Lieutenant, see to the office workers.
遵命，老大
It's being done, Herr.
[德语]
老天，我们在诺克斯堡里
一兆四千亿美金
140 billion dollars!
是肯塔基的十倍
Ten times what's in Kentucky!
诺克斯堡
Fort Knox!
是给观光客看的地方
Ha! It's for tourists!
麦克连
McClane!
约翰，你体力不行了
John, you out of shape?
你差一点没赶到
You barely made it.
是，差一点没赶到
Yeah, well, we all barely make it.
你要我们做什么？
What do you want us to do?
什么是四只脚随时预备旅行？
What has four legs and is always ready to travel?
什么？
Huh? What?
他说什么？
What'd he say?
什么是四只脚随时预备旅行？
What has four legs and is always ready to travel?
搞什么？你难道没有孩子？
What's the matter with you? Don't you have kids?
那是个大象的笑话
That's an elephant joke.
那个就是炸弹了？
Whoa. That a bomb?
是的，你过去拿吧
Yeah, just go ahead and grab it.
你是警察
Well, you're the cop.
赛门说在这件事上你要帮忙
Simon said you're supposed to be helping with this.
我在帮忙
I'm helpin'.
什么时候才要开始帮忙？
Well, when you gonna start helpin'?
在你拿到炸弹之后
After you get the bomb.
小心
Careful.
会小心的
I'm being careful.
别打开它
Don't open it!
什么？
What?
我必须打开它
I gotta open it.
不会有事的
Everything's gonna be all right.
（我是炸弹 你刚启动了我）
狗屎，我就说别打开
Shit! Shit! I told you not to open it!
我想你们已收到了讯息
I trust you see the message.
它有遥控回路，所以请你们别跑
It has a proximity circuit, so, please, don't run.
我知道了，我们不会跑
Yeah, I got it. We're not gonna run.
如何停止爆炸？
How do we turn this thing off?
喷泉那有两个桶子，看到了吗？
On the fountain there should be two jugs.
一个五加仑、一个三加仑
Do you see them? A five-gallon and a three-gallon.
在其中之一装四加仑水放在秤上
Fill one of the jugs with exactly four gallons of water...
计时器自然会停止
and place it on the scale, and the timer will stop.
必须正确，太多太少都会引爆它
ou must be precise. One ounce more or less will result in detonation.
假如五分钟后你们还活着 我会再打来
If you're still alive in five minutes, we'll speak again.
等一下
Wait! Wait a second!
我没听懂，你听懂了吗？
I don't get it. Do you get it?
不懂
No.
去拿桶子
Get the jugs.
显然我们不能用三加仑桶去装四加仑
Obviously, we can't fill the three-gallon jug with four gallons of water, right?
很显然
Obviously.
我晓得了，这么办
All right, I know. Here we go.
我们把三加仑桶装满，对吧？
We fill the three-gallon jug exactly to the top, right?
再把三加仑桶倒入五加仑桶
Okay, now, we pour that three gallons into the five-gallon jug...
那五加仑桶就正好有三加仑
giving us exactly three gallons in the five-gallon jug, right?
没错，然后呢？
Right. Then what?
然后在三加仑桶内装三分之一…
Now, we take...the three-gallon jug, we fill that a third of the way up...
不行，他说必须要准确是四加仑
No, no, no, he said be precise.
我跑了几里路后还要玩孩子游戏
Every cop in 15 miles is runnin' his ass off, and I'm out here playin' kids' games in the park!
你要专心解决手上的问题？
Hey! You wanna focus on the problem at hand?
你说你知道，还叫我别开口
I thought you said you knew! You said don't say anything if you don't know!
把桶子给我，我们从头开始
I thought you said... Give me the fuckin' jug! We're starting over.
不行，我们不能再从头开始
No, we can't start over.
把桶子放下来，你这笨王八…
I'm gonna put my foot up your ass, you dumb mother...
说啊，说出来啊！
Say it! Say it!
你要叫我黑鬼，对吧？
You were gonna call me a "nigger," weren't you?
我没有
No, I wasn't.
你有
Yes, you were!
否则你要叫我什么？
What were you gonna call me?
混球！叫你混球，如何？
Asshole! How's that, asshole?
因我是白人所以你有心结，宙斯
You got some fuckin' problem with me because I'm white, Zeus?
是不是那样？我对你有偏见吗？
Is that it, huh? Have I oppressed you?
我对你的同胞有偏见吗？
Have I oppressed your people somehow?
我告诉你你有什么问题
I'll tell you what your problem is, you don't like me 'cause...
你有种族歧视
You're a racist!
什么
What?
你有种族歧视
You're a racist!
因我是白人所以你不喜欢我
You don't like me 'cause I'm white!
我不喜欢你是因你会害我送命
I don't like you because you're gonna get me killed!
剩下多少分钟？
How much time?
狗屎，我们剩下不到一分钟了
Oh, shit! We got less than a minute!
把那东西丢掉
Throw this thing away.
我们不能，否则会引爆它
Look, we can't take it off of there. It'll detonate.
等一下 等会儿
Just wait. Wait a second, wait a second.
我想出来，里面有两加仑，对吧
I got it, I got it! Exactly two gallons in here, right?
对
Right.
剩下一加仑的空间，对吧
Leaving exactly one gallon of empty space, right?
对
Yeah.
这里是五加仑整，对吧？
A full five gallons here, right?
把五加仑倒一加仑出来
You pour one gallon out of the five gallons into there...
就刚刚好四加仑
we have exactly four gallons in there!
我们快点倒过去
Pour it in there! Come on!
倒啊
Come on!
别倒洒了
Don't spill! Don't spill it!
行了，正好四加仑
Good, good, good! Exactly four gallons!
你办到了，麦克连
You did it, McClane!
把它放到秤上去
Put it on the thing! Get it down there!
狗屎
Fuck you.
（解除）
恭喜，你们还活着
Congratulations. You're still alive.
恭喜
Congratulations.
是的，我们办到了
Yeah, we did it.
再次令我讶异，约翰
You surprised me again, John.
这快变成我的嗜好了
This is becoming an ugly habit.
我没那种时间，赛门，听我说…
Yeah, well, I don't have the time right now, Simon. Listen.
我们说好的，那炸弹在那里？
A deal's a deal. Where's the school bomb?
正好相反，时间还很充裕
On the contrary, you have lots of time.
你有…
You have
两小时四十七分钟
two hours and 47 minutes, precisely.
那些是测试你的智慧的时间
Plenty of time to test those wits of yours.
听着，混蛋，我该死的宿醉未醒
Hey, listen, jerk-off! Let me tell you something! I got a bad fuckin' hangover, all right?
我已经厌倦玩游戏了，炸弹在那？
And I'm a little sick of these fuckin' riddles! Now, where is the school bomb?
控制脾气，约翰 通向真理的道路有许多转折
Temper, John. The road to truth has many turns.
喷泉大象雕像下面有只信封
You will find an envelope under the rim of the fountain.
当你依上面建议的路线行走时
When you undertake the trip it suggests...
同时间想这个问题
ask yourself this question:
什么是42里的21？
What is 21 out of 42?
我们已经落后进步了
We're behind.
我们应放弃其他的，离开这里
We should abandon the rest and go.
放轻松点，塔戈
Relax, Targo.
二十条街之内没有任何警察
There's not a cop for 20 blocks.
派主场队到洋基体育馆去
He's sending us to the home-team dugout at Yankee Stadium. Why?
我们是主场队，还有什么吗？
Well, we're the home team. We supposed to find something there?
什么是42里的21？
What's 21 out of 42?
21是42的一半，什么的42？
21 again. Half of 42. 42 what?
洋基队有多少球员？
How many players are on the Yankees ball club?
25个
Twenty-five.
还有什么是21的？
What else is 21?
21点
Blackjack.
有个俱乐部叫21点
It's a club.
完全在瞎猜
It's a wild-goose chase, is what it is.
最近的车站在那？
Where is the nearest A train?
等一下，也许会有小孩子拿走它
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. You know, some kid might find that.
你说的没错
You're right.
给我过来，你们两个小王八蛋
Come back here! You little sons of bitches!
我会记住你们的
I remember you!
你们要去那？你们在干什么？
Hey, where you going? Come here. What are you doing?
放开我，猪头
Don't! Let me go, dick-head!
说话小心点
Watch your mouth!
要为糖果去住少年感化院？
You want to go down to juvenile hall for a Butterfinger? Is that it?
看看四周，一个警察也没有
Look around, man. All the cops are into something.
像圣诞节一样 我能把市政府偷走
It's Christmas! You could steal City Hall!
走，我们走
Let's go! Come on!
那是我的脚踏车
Whoa, that's my bike!
你要去那？我以为要去地铁车站
Where you going? Yankee Stadium's that way!
那是我的脚踏车，混球
That's my bike, you asshole!
你们干嘛不辗过街上的每一个人
Why don't you just run over everybody in the whole street?
麦克连
McClane,
我们干嘛回到这里来？
what the fuck are we doing back down here?
让我问你一件事
Let me ask you something.
华尔街没有什么？
What is it that Wall Street doesn't have?
怎么连你也开始玩猜谜游戏了？
What, is this stuff catching? You're talkin' in riddles!
别打岔，华尔街没有什么？
No, stay with me. What is it that Wall Street does not have?
没什么？
What?
没有学校
Schools.
华尔街有很多的是什么？
And what is it they have a shitload of?
是什么？
What?
（联邦准备银行）
我马上回来
I'll be back in a minute.
我该拿这个怎么办？
What am I supposed to do with this?
交给那边的那几个人
Give it to those guys over there.
他来了
He's here.
你得说清楚一点
Perhaps you could be a little more specific.
麦克连来了，他正走向银行
McClane is here. He's walking toward the bank.
那黑人则朝我而来
The black man is coming toward me.
那真可惜
Oh, now, that's a pity.
我叫他们去体育馆的
And after we'd gone to all that trouble at the stadium.
赛门，杀了他，别再和他玩了
Simon, kill him. Stop toying with him,
现在就把他杀了
and kill him now.
好了，就这样吧，愿他安息
Okay, so be it. May he rest in peace.
艾林还有四个人在大厅
I'll inform Karl in the lobby.
你们收拾一下离开那里
You pack up your team and get out of there.
这一个呢？
And this one?
警员先生
Officer?
恐怕那件事上我需要答案
Yeah, I'm I'm afraid I'm going to need an answer on that issue.
让他走
Let him go.
了解
Understood.
什么事？
Yes, sir?
约翰麦克连要我把这个给你们
John McClane says to give you this.
老天，别打开，是颗炸弹
Wait, wait. Jesus, don't open it. It's a bomb.
另一个？
Another?
我知道了，我们会料理的
Yeah. Oh, I see. Um, oh, we'll take care of that.
我们必须走了
We'd better move now.
先生，谢谢你的协助，感谢之至
Sir, thank you so much for your assistance. We really appreciate it. Thank you.
你在干什么？
我不要和它共乘一车
小孩子可能…
把它放在后面
你们就这样离开这了？
Hey! You, you, uh, leaving this place unguarded?
我了解
你好吗？
How you doing?
还好
All right.
纽约警局，约翰麦克连
John McClane, NYPD.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
没事，今天是洗衣日
Yes. Laundry day.
有何效劳之处？警官
What can I do for you, Lieutenant?
今天一早上都那么安静吗？
Has it been quiet like this all morning here?
除了两小时前的爆炸之外
Except for that big explosion a couple of hours ago.
在过去一小时没什么奇怪的事？
I mean, have you seen anything strange happen in the last hour or so?
没有
No.
而且这里还有警察
And we've had cops in here pretty steady
地铁出事后他们就一直在那
since the subway thing.
我们正要去金库层巡逻
We were just gonna make a round on the vault floor...
假如你想一道来的话
if you want to tag along.
当然
Sure, yeah,
我要去
that's... Think I will.
你认为天气情况如何？
Yeah, what do you think of this heat this late in the year?
夏天到了
Yeah, Indian summer, huh?
好像待会要下“大盆倾雨”
Yeah, feels like it's gonna rain like dogs and cats later.
这是你们的人
Here's one of your guys.
阿道刑警，对吧？
Detective, uh, Otto, isn't it?
约翰麦克连
John McClane.
你在干什么？
Hey, Mike, how you doing?
有时我想走楼梯，运动一下
I keep telling myself I'm gonna take the stairs just for the exercise...
像今天这种天
but on a hot day like this...
似乎还是搭电梯比较好
But it seems like I always end up riding the lift.
昨晚乐透开几号？
Hey, what was the lottery number last night?
有人玩乐透吗？
Huh? You guys play the lottery? No?
我太太每周替我买两张乐透彩券
Yeah, my wife buys me two tickets every week,
过去十年都买同样的号码
for the last ten years. Plays the same two numbers all the time.
我问她为何不买别的号码？
I say, "Honey, why don't you play a different number?"
她说那是她的幸运号码
She goes, "Well, those are my lucky numbers."
彩券就在这
I got the tickets right here.
把枪放下！现在就放下
Put that fucking gun down! Put the fucking gun down now!
放下
Put it down!
哈罗，下面有人吗？
Hello! Anybody down here?
把手举起来！马上！
Put your hands up! Put your fucking hands up now!
不，约翰，不
No! No! No, John, no! No!
老天，你差点让我心脏病发作
Jesus Christ, you almost gave me a heart attack.
你没事吧？
You all right?
那不是我的血
Yeah, yeah, it's not my blood.
这下面是怎么回事
What the hell's going on down here?
你四处去看看吧
Go take a look in there.
麦克连，大伙都到那去了？
Hey, McClane, where the hell is everybody?
去他的赛门说
Simon fuckin' says!
我早该想到了
I should've seen it coming a mile away.
这根本不是什么复仇
This was never about revenge.
而是抢劫
It's about a goddamn heist!
那些房间是装什么的？
But wh... what was in the room?
装这个
This.
这是什么？
What is this?
该死，这是黄金？
Oh, shit! Is this gold?
是的
Yeah, it's gold.
这真的很重
Damn, this is heavy!
他们弄走一屋子的这个？
hey cleaned out a whole room of this?
是的
Yeah.
那需要货柜或…
You know, that would've taken, like, a-a-a-a tank...
倾卸车
A dump truck.
十四辆大倾卸车
Fourteen great big dump trucks.
我们差点被倾卸车撞到
We almost got hit by a dump truck.
狗屎
Shit!
慢一点
Damn! Slow down! Shit!
把那东西放下来
Put that shit down.
门都没有
No fucking way.
他们不会让你留着的
They ain't gonna let you keep it.
等着瞧吧
Yeah, yeah, we'll see.
我们需要一辆车
We're gonna need a car.
一辆车？
A car?
你知道怎么接通点火吗？
You know how to hot-wire this thing?
我当然会，我是电气技师
Of course I can. I'm an electrician.
唯一的问题是…
Only problem is...
花的时间太长
it takes too fucking long.
不在桥上
They're not on the bridge!
在下面，麦克连，在罗斯福路上
Down there, McClane! The FDR!
我们走，快点
Let's go! Let's go! Come on!
狗屎
Ah, shit!
怎么啦？
What?
我把电话摔坏了
They shot the phone.
太不幸了
Ah, too bad.
什么是42里的21？
Come on, what's 21 out of 42?
毫无头绪
I don't have a clue.
洋基体育馆呢？
Well, what about Yankee Stadium?
我们会去那里，但那不重要
We'll get there...
不能让那混蛋离开曼哈顿
but that son of a bitch is not getting off of Manhattan!
开快点
Move!
老天，你以为你是希拉里？
Jesus Christ! Who do you think you are, lady? Hillary Clinton?
有了，柯林顿夫人，42任总统
That's it!  Hillary Clinton! The 42nd president!
她应该是第43任总统
No, she'd be the 43rd president.
随便啦，但谁是第21任？
All right, all right, but who's the 21st?
我不知道
I don't know, l...
你不知道？
You don't know?
我不知道，你知道吗？
No, I don't know. Do you know?
我不知道
No!
这辆车的引擎太烂了，加速啊
What kind of engine's this piece of shit have? Come on. Step on it!
没有它那里也去不了，稍安勿燥
It's just a Yugo! It's built for economy not speed!
你干什么？
Whoa! What are you doing?
再找个电话
I'm going to get us another phone.
等一下
Hey, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait!
谁是第21任总统？
Hey, who was the 21st president?
你去死
Go fuck yourself!
那家伙火大了
That guy was pissed.
你的东西留在后座了
He'll feel better when he looks in the back seat.
狗屎，那是我的金条
Oh, shit! That was my gold bar!
我是麦克连，接华特柯督察
This is McClane. Get me Inspector Walter Cobb.
约翰，你在那里？
John, where the hell are you?
华特，不是复仇，是抢劫
Walter, it's not a revenge! It's a heist!
什么？
What?
联邦准备银行的金库有黄金
There's gold in the Federal Reserve...
他们搞走了一大堆
and they took a shitload of it!
他们驾倾卸车朝北走
They're headed north in dump trucks!
你喝酒了吗？麦克连
Have you been drinking, McClane?
自今天早上起就没喝了
No, not since this morning.
罗斯福路和70街上有倾卸车队
Listen, there's a line of dump trucks northbound on the FDR at about 70th Street.
快关闭桥梁，派直升机到那去
You ought to close the bridge and then get some helicopters over there right away!
我现在连热狗摊也赶不走
I couldn't close a hot dog stand right now!
警力全散开了
I'm spread all over hell!
这个炸弹要怎么办？
What about this damn bomb?
查出来谁是第21任总统
Find out who the 21st president was.
和他有关系
It's got something to do with this!
约翰，第21任什么？
John? John, the 21st what?
华特
Walter!
狗屎，什么烂电话
Shit! Goddamn cellular fuckin' phones!
去找门罗，叫他把59街以来
Get hold of Munsen in Triborough.
所有的桥梁都封闭掉
Tell him to close all the East River bridges north of 59th Street.
找倾卸车
Looking for dump trucks.
倾卸车？
Dump trucks?
麦克连说倾卸车在罗斯福路上
McClane says...there are dump trucks headed up the FDR
装了满车的黄金
loaded with gold.
华特，罗斯福路禁行倾卸车
Walter, they don't allow dump trucks on the FDR!
去做
Connie!
行，你不要我争我就不争
All right! You don't want I should argue...
不论是多愚蠢的事
I won't argue, no matter how stupid it is!
警犬队，到后面去查锅炉室
Canine, bring it around to the back, check out the boiler room.
找到什么了吗？查理
Find anything, Charlie?
拿着X光机在这待一个星期
I could spend a week in here with an X-ray machine
还是什么都找不到
and still not find it.
你没有一星期，查理，五分钟
You don't have a week, Charlie. You got five more minutes,
然后我就要到86街去了
then we're moving up to 86th street.
我们已经尽快在这了
We're going as fast as we can.
什么事？
What's up?
麦克连提到联邦准备银行大厦
McClane was mentioning something about the Federal Reserve building.
那不就在华尔街爆炸案范围内？
Isn't that right near that Wall Street bomb site we just left?
你要我们在这待多久？
How long do you want us to stay here?
在体育馆的人，撤还是留？
The men at the stadium, stay or go?
卡尔现在应该要回报了
Karl should have checked in by now.
快啊
Come on, come on.
留在原处，麦克连也许会出现
Stay where you are. McClane may still turn up.
放轻松，塔戈
Relax, Targo.
他就算还活着也不会和别人讲话
If he is still alive...he won't be talking to anyone.
下一个出口
It's the next turnoff.
自由发表，你在播出了，什么事
Hi, it's Elvis Duran, you're on the air. What's up?
首先我要告诉你节目有多精彩
First of all, I just want to tell you what a great show you've got.
我一直都在听你的节目
I listen to you all the time.
谢谢，你想谈什么？
Thank you, thank you. What do you want to talk about?
你知道目前警察到处跑来跑去
Well, you know, all those cop cars screaming around everywhere?
晓得他们在干什么吗？
You know what they're up to?
在某学校有一颗炸弹
There's a bomb in a school.
我表哥是警察
My cousin's a cop.
有人在某学校放了颗大炸弹
Somebody put a big bomb in a school somewhere.
只是他们不知是那所学校
Only they don't know which one...
于是搜索每一座学校
so they're searching all of them.
在纽约市的每一所学校
Every school in the metropolitan area.
我的老天
Holy shit.
朵瑞丝
Doris?
安妮
Annie?
朵瑞丝，能联络上我太太吗？
Doris, can you get ahold of my wife?
特利，半座城市在找911
Turley! Half the goddamn city just called 911!
它们不见了
They've gone.
什么？
What?
它们不见了
They're gone!
这家伙是谁？胡迪尼？
Who is this guy, Houdini?
狗屎
Shit!
在那边
Down there! Down there!
这玩意有安全气囊吗？
This thing got air bags?
应该有，我的车有，我不知…
Your side does. I don't know about mi...
麦克连…
McClane!
卡车里的人让我看见你的手
In the truck, let me see the hands!
放在车门上
Put them on the door!
别杀我
Don't kill me! Don't shoot me!
你是卡车司机？
You the truck driver?
不，我是美容家，我当然是司机
No, I'm a beautician. Of course, I'm a truck driver!
你要把这辆卡车开到那里去？
Where you taking this truck?
下水道
The aqueduct.
你把倾卸车开去下水道干什么？
What are you taking a dump truck to the racetrack for?
不，是污水下水道
No, the aqueduct! The a... Th-The water aqueduct!
下水道？
Aqueduct?
看到吗？由这直通凯斯密山
See? It goes from here all the way up to the Catskill Mountains.
什么东西？
What does?
那边，水管延伸到六十里长
That! The water pipe. Goes for about 60 miles.
你是工头？
Hey, you the foreman?
纽约市警察
NYPD.
过去几分钟有倾卸车通过吗？
You had any, like, extra dump trucks come through here in the last couple of minutes?
我要开罚单给它们
I'm gonna write those fucking clowns up!
不听指挥
They better start paying attention to work orders...
你在说什么？
Who-Who are you talking about?
有十二辆冲进水管里去了
Ah, the dozen idiots who tore ass up the tube.
我们已经不再在那里装了
We're not loading up there anymore.
我们在这里装
We're loading over here!
怪不得不走桥，不怕直升机
So much for bridges and helicopters.
有地图显示隧道通到那吗？
You got a map showin' me where this tunnel goes?
就在这
Yeah, right here.
我们由锯木厂开始到考佛坝
We run pretty much up under the sawmill until you get up to the Coffer Dam.
由那里我们已经把水接通了
From there on, we've already brought the water down from the reservoir.
有任何方法能进出那里吗？
Any way to get in or out of there?
每隔两里有一个通风口
Yeah, there's a vent shaft every two miles.
我是指卡车
No, I mean with a truck.
到了考佛坝，卡车可以进出
At the Coffer Dam. You can get a truck in there.
沿着沙尔公园路走，大概二十里路
Just follow the Sawmill River Parkway up there. It's about 20 miles.
我和你在那边见，行吗？
All right, I'm gonna meet you right there. All right?
等一下，我要做什么？
Wait, wait! Wh-What am I supposed to do?
你要去洋基体育馆
You're going to go up to Yankee Stadium!
麦克连…
McClane!
快走，我们剩下不到二小时
Go! Get out of here! We got less than two hours!
妈的
Goddamn it!
出了什么问题吗？
Hey! Is somethin' wrong?
我们移走480码的岩块
480 yards of rock moved so far.
那是胡佛坝的十倍
Now that's ten times the Hoover Dam.
我们头顶上有516尺厚的岩块
Right now, there's 516 feet of rock above our heads.
这部份是三号隧道的第三阶段
This part is phase three of tunnel three.
自1954年开始设计
Planning for it began back in 1954...
到1970年六月才开始动工
but construction didn't begin until June of 1970.
你知道三号道最有趣的是什么吗？
You know what the most interesting part of tunnel three is?
是什么？杰瑞
What's that, Jerry?
是通气口，每个通风口…
The valves. Each one...
…自一、二号隧道离开
...a big departure from tunnels one and two.
快点啊！
Come on!
真是抛锚的好地方
What a hell of a place to break down.
等一下，杰瑞
Hold it a minute, Jerry.
把你的安全帽给我
Let me have your hard hat.
有外套吗？杰瑞
You got a jacket?
在这
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Here.
在这等一会儿
Wait here a minute.
等他走到门旁的时候
Wait until he gets alongside the door.
各位，米奇欧布莱，安全官
Hey, fellas, Mickey O'Brien, aqueduct security.
我们接获报告说有人闯进来 呃…骑着八只驯鹿
Hey, listen, we had a report of a guy comin' through here with, uh, eight reindeer...
说是个留雪白胡子的肥老头子
Yeah, they said he was a jolly, old fat guy...
穿着红白衣服
with a snowy white beard, cute, little red and white suit.
很讶异你们没看到他
I'm surprised you didn't see him.
这些家伙原来是用电话
What's with you guys and these phones?
应该还有别的东西
Maybe this'll give me something.
老天，那家伙死了吗？
Holy shit! Is that guy dead?
杰瑞，我想他是死了
Yes, Jerry, I'm afraid he is.
老天
Jesus Christ.
我要你去找一个姓柯的督察
I want you to get ahold of a guy named Cobb. Walter Cobb. C-o-b-b.
他是我的上司，叫他赶到这里来
He's the head of my police unit. Get him down here.
说是约翰麦克连叫你去的
Find him. Tell him you were with John McClane.
叫他查出谁是第21任总统？
Tell him to find out who the 21st president was.
切斯特·A·亚瑟
Chester A. Arthur.
什么？
What?
切斯特·A·亚瑟
Chester A. Arthur.
1881年到1885年
1881-1885.
1880年被提名当选副总统
Nominated vice president in 1880.
你知道他是纽约海关关员吗？
Did you know he was Collector of Customs right here in New York?
我不知道，杰瑞，保重
No, I didn't know that, Jerry. Take care of yourself.
现在？
不，只有其中一个人
（游戏结束）
要还是不要
不要
我们跟踪他
电视在播我们
TV's got us! TV's got us!
得先让这些交通队的人先走
We got to release these traffic guys!
不行，交通队能照顾自己
No! Traffic jams we can take care of later.
去查一下这玩意有什么不对？
You find out what the hell is wrong with this thing!
频率拥塞
Frequencies are jammed!
瑞奇呢？
What about Ricky?
我不知道，我联络不到他
I don't know. I can't get ahold of him.
但华特，联邦准备银行…
But, Walter, Federal Reserve...
存放着全世界的黄金储备
Biggest gold storage in the world.
派一组人到那去，找到瑞奇
You get a unit back down there. Find Ricky.
查出来出了什么事
Find out what the hell is going on.
华特
Walter!
你得听听这个
You gotta hear this!
我还以为我们是走后门
Christ, I thought we were going in the back way.
这就是后门，华特
This is the back way, Walter.
半小时后全市的校园都会有暴动
In half an hour, you're going to have a riot at every school in this city!
（切斯特·A·亚瑟国民学校）
我们由顶楼开始，每层二十人
We'll start at the top floor, put 20 men on each floor.
另外五十人和我们到地下室去
Send the other 50 men down to the basement with us.
电话如何？
What about McClane?
什么都没，占线的信号
Not a word. I'm gettin' nothing. Busy signals.
切斯特可能是最糟的…
Westchester's probably worse than we are.
我们有点是孤注一掷，对吧？
This is kind of putting all our eggs in one basket, isn't it?
我是说万一麦克连错了呢？
I mean, what if McClane's wrong?
华特，这是马丁奈兹校长
Walter! This is Principal Martinez.
马丁奈兹校长，柯督察
Principal Martinez, Inspector Cobb.
督察，你好
How do you do, Inspector?
你好，校长
How do you do, Principal Martinez?
我不想让你的孩子们紧张
I don't want to alarm your children. I wonder if you...
我要你把他们都带去礼堂
could move them all into the auditorium
让他们保持冷静
and keep them calm.
我们接近水坝了，可以叫后卫了
We're coming to the dam. You can call the rear guard.
狄尔，你可以后撤了
Rear guard, you can close up now.
我们已通过了水坝，可以后撤了
We've reached the dam. You can come up now.
缪斯
Nils,
你可以后撤了
you can close in now.
缪斯
Nils!
注意，缪斯已经死了
Attention, attention, Nils is dead.
我重复，缪斯已死了，帕尔也死了
I repeat, Nils is dead, fuckhead. So is his pal.
还有自东德来的那四个人
And those four guys from the East German all-stars?
你留在银行的那些人会慢一点
Your boys down at the bank? They're gonna be a little late.
约翰
John,
你开的那卡车有一百三十亿黄金
in the back of the truck you're driving there's 13 billion dollars' worth in gold bullion.
不晓得是否能打个交道？
I wonder, would a deal be out of the question?
我有个提议 你趴在石头上
Yeah, I got a deal for you. Crawl out from under that rock
我开车从你屁股上碾过去
you're hidin' under, and I'll drive this truck up your ass.
真多采多姿
How colorful.
我告诉过你别和他玩
I told you not to toy with him!
谢谢，那真的很有帮助
Thank you. That's very helpful.
你会危急整次行动和合约
You'll jeopardize the mission and the contract!
上船之前我们容易受伤害
We're vulnerable 'til we reach the ship!
我要把此事做一个了结
I'm going to put an end to this.
住手
Stop!
塔戈，到这边来
Targo! Targo! Here! Come here!
我们把水坝炸掉
We blow the dam!
什么？
What?
我们淹死他
We drown him!
华特
Walter!
看看这个
Take a look at this.
早上十点半送来的
The janitor said this one was delivered this morning about 10:30, right?
没有接上线
It's not hooked up.
再来看看前面
Okay. Now take a look at the front.
我们钻开铰链，叫大家出去
Okay, we drill the hinges. Get everybody out!
麦克连
McClane!
你在那？
Where are you?
我在这
Over here!
你真是有办法回到地面上来
You got a hell of a way of flagging somebody down!
你没事吧？
You all right?
你去过洋基体育馆了吗？
Did you go to Yankee Stadium?
去了，那里没有人
Yeah, there's nobody there!
你确定没有人？
You didn't see nobody?
是的
No!
没有人跟踪你？
Nobody was following you?
我告诉你是他在恶整我们
I'm telling you, he's jerking us around!
狗屎
Oh, shit,
快啊！
Come on, come on!
还说没有人跟踪你
Nobody's following us!
走！走！走！
Let's go! Go! Go!
行了，拉开吧
It's not rigged. Pull it.
（解除引爆密码）
我说你可以停止搜索了
Well, I'd say you could call off your search.
你能让它停下来吗？
Can you stop it?
我甚至不该碰它
I shouldn't even touch it.
谁晓得这玩意装了什么诡雷
Who knows what kind of booby traps this thing's got.
密码呢？
What about the code?
没有消息
No word.
我们何时疏散？
When do we evacuate?
赛门说有学童离开他就引爆
Simon says he sees one kid leave the building, boom!
当然有还在监视下的风险
Fine! There's a chance that somebody's still watching,
但我们不能坐以待毙啊！
but we can't stand here with our thumb up our ass, waiting for this freaking thing to blow up!
好
Okay.
狗屎
Shit! Shit!
头低一点
Get your head down!
开快一点
Come on, Zeus! Hold it steady! Hold it steady!
快！快！
Go! Go!
别挡路
Outta the way!
超过去
Go around 'em! Go around 'em!
我查出来谁是第21任总统了
I found out who was the 21st president!
谁？
Who?
切斯特·A·亚瑟
Some guy named Arthur.
切斯特·A·亚瑟？
Chester A. Arthur?
没错，你可以再说一次
Chester A. Arthur, that's it, yeah.
切斯特·A·亚瑟国民学校？
Chester A. Arthur Elementary School?
没错
Yeah, that's it.
大家注意，我知道周五才会集合
Hi, kids. I know you usually have assembly on Fridays,
但今天是特别的日子
but today is special.
蓝柏先生是消防队的
Mr.Lambert here is from the fire department...
他要做一次全新的消防演习
and today he wants us to practice a brand-new fire drill.
所以我要你们分成两组
So, I want you to divide in half,
一组到那边靠着墙排成一行
and I want half of you to go over here.
另一组到那边去
The other half will go in this direction.
请你们又快又安静的做好，好吗
Please do it very quietly and very quickly, all right?
大家站起来，老师请协助一下
Everybody, up, please. Teachers, please help them.
消防演习个屁，他不是消防队的
Fire drill, my ass. That guy ain't from the fire department.
也许是收音机的那件事
Maybe it's because of the radio.
你是说他们在抓我们？不
You mean, like, they're after us? No.
东尼把我们供出来了
Tony squealed on us.
不，他没有
No, he didn't.
走吧
Come on.
你去那？
Where you going?
让我开
Let me drive! Let me drive!
妈的
Goddamn it!
你以前为何不告诉我？
Why the hell didn't you tell me before?
他当然会炸掉那所学校
Of course he put the bomb up in that school!
他为何要那么做？
Why would he do that?
因为要吸引警方的注意力
Make sure he got your complete attention!
找保险丝盒
Find the fuse panel! Where...
什么？
What?
保险丝盒，保险丝盒在那？
The fuse panel! Where's the fuse panel on this car?
就在这
It's right here. Right here.
把引擎的保险丝拆下来
Pull out the anti-Iock brakes fuse!
我不知道那一个是引擎的
Shit! I don't know which one it is!
那就把它全都拆掉
Well, then yank them all out then!
头低下来，情况会很糟
Put your head down! Put your head fucking down! This is gonna be really bad.
听我说，抓稳了，行吗？
Listen to me. Hang the fuck on, all right?
发生了什么事？
Oh! Oh! What the fuck happened?
你有最高级的车子
You got a triple-A card?
借过
Excuse me.
继续找
Keep moving.
校工在最后一次检查所有建筑物
I've got the janitors making a last sweep of the building right now.
谢谢，马丁奈兹校长
Thank you, Ms. Martinez.
出来吧
Come on.
你一张，他一张…
All right, five-card stud, threes and nines are wild.
保持低姿势
Stay down! Stay low!
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
询问他
Interrogating him.
他会告诉你什么？我已经死了
Well, what's he gonna tell you? "I'm dead."
我不知道，所以我才会问他
Well, I ain't gonna know 'til I ask him, am I?
绕过去看杂物箱内
Go around and see
是否有阿斯匹灵
if there's any aspirins in that glove box.
门都没有，你去找
No way. You do it.
十个两毛五，倾卸车那个人也有
Ten quarters. The guy in the dump truck had ten quarters.
也许是要打长途电话
Well, maybe they were making long-distance phone calls.
不是，是过桥费
No. It's for the bridge. It's for the toll on the bridge!
在那，在墙边，倾卸车，就在那
There! There! Down on the wharf! Dump trucks! Right there!
老天，他们已经装上船了
Christ! They got it loaded on the ship already!
狗屎，海岸防卫队呢？
Shit! How about the Coast Guard?
要一小时才会到
It'd take 'em an hour to get here.
狗屎！
Shit! Shit!
我们可以跳下去
We can jump!
什么？
What?
我们可以跳下去
We can jump!
你疯了，离甲板有一百尺
You're out of your fucking mind! It's 100 feet down to the deck!
但到吊杆没那么远
Yeah, but not to the crane it isn't.
钢缆会把你切成两半
The cables'd cut you in half.
我办得到
I can make it.
胡扯，下来，看看车上有什么
Bullshit. Get down. Look in the back of that car for some gloves.
六个诡雷，四条死胡同
Six booby traps, four dead ends...
还有部份是真的通路
and a partridge in a pear tree.
好了，亲爱滴，我们开始吧
Okay, honey, let's dance.
我们要像赛跑那样
We're gonna have sort of a race.
当我说跑的时候，你们拚命向前跑
So, when I say go, I want you all to run like crazy.
跟着警察及消防队员
All of you, you follow the police officer and the firemen.
你们是我的领队
You guys are my front runners, okay?
华特，我想我们要动身了
Walter, think we're cutting this a little thin?
不，乔，我们等
No, Joe, we're gonna wait!
麦克连还在设法找密码
McClane still may get the code.
我要勾在那里？
Line me up with that crane.
勾在那边，就是那边
There! There! Right there! Right there!
就在那边，你的位置还可以
Right there, you're okay.
我看到它了
All right. I see it now, I see it.
狗屎，这需要奇迹才行
Shit! This is gonna take a miracle!
双手合十吧
Keep your fingers crossed. Okay, swing it.
稳住，你快勾到了
Okay, come on, come on, you almost got it. Almost, almost.
行了
Yeah, all right!
你要去那？在赶什么吗？
Where you going? Are you in a hurry?
这次我先下去，行吗？
I'm going first this time, all right?
新闻界来了，长官
We have the intercom rigged, sir.
华特，孩子们也许没问题
Walter, the kids may be fine, but you wait much longer...
再不出发我都要尿裤子了
and I'm gonna pee in my pants!
我们要等，康妮
We're gonna wait, Connie.
再等六分钟
Six more minutes.
麦克连
Yo, McClane.
什么事
What?
那下面
Down there.
狗屎
Oh, shit!
快，快，快
Go, go, go, man! Go, go, go!
老天，谢谢你说服我别跳
Oh, boy! Am I glad you talked me out of jumping.
抬他的脚
Oh, fuck. Get his feet.
有些东西你们得看一下
待会
很重要
不行，现在
这是在货柜里的东西
我们去找赛门逼问那密码
We go find Simon, drag him to the ship-to-shore radio...
拿着这个
and beat that fucking code out of him. Here, take this.
它怎么用？
How's it work?
你不会开枪？
You don't know how to shoot a gun?
我们黑人不是全都会用枪
Look, all brothers don't know how to shoot guns,
你这种族歧视的混球
you racist motherfucker.
告我吧，把那往后拉再扣扳机
Sue me. Just yank back on that and pull the trigger.
如此而已
That's it.
如此而已？
That's it?
如此而己，别射到自己了
That's it. Just don't shoot yourself.
别逞英雄，找到他就来找我
Hey, don't be no hero. You find 'em, you come get me.
设定好自动驾驶了吗？
You have the autopilot set?
好了，长官
Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
别动
Don't fuckin' move!
撒马利亚人
Oh, the Samaritan.
把密码给我
Give me the goddamn code!
密码？
Code?
你是说为了学校那件事？
Oh! You mean for the school?
抱歉，我不能那么做
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
你现在就叫人取消密码
You call in that code...
否则我把你这变态轰下地狱
right now, or I blow your sick ass into the next world!
假如那是你得做的…
If that's what you gotta do.
得先开保险
You gotta take the safety catch off.
老天
Oh! Goddamn!
那才能开枪，麦克连在那？
See? That works. Now, where's McClane?
你说什么？
What was that?
他说别开枪
He said, "Don't shoot."
好，查理，我们要疏散了
Okay, Charlie, we're gonna have to go with the evacuation.
我们动身
We're gonna go!
你们听到他说的了
Well, you heard the man! Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
我们动身
We're gonna go!
听我的口令
On my mark!
五、四、三、二、一、动身
Five, four, three, two, one, go!
走！走！走！
Come on! Let's go! Let's go! Hustle!
我们动身吧！大伙们走！
Let's do it! Okay, gang, let's go!
跑！跑！跑！大家跑快点！
Go. Go, go! Hip-hop! Hip-hop! Come on, everybody! Let's go!
他们在干嘛？
What are they doing?
你们要去那？
Yo! Where you goin'?
Hey, where you goin'?
我每次都以为杀死你了
I see you all dead, little man, policeman...
但你总是阴魂不散
and you don't go away.
我不是那么容易放弃的，朋友
Yeah, I'm that fucking Energizer bunny.
你现在要去那？
Where are you going now, huh?
要逮捕我吗？
我想我不会逮捕你
I don't think I'm gonna arrest you.
我早知道是胡扯，没人在监视
I knew it was bullshit. There's nobody watching.
该把查理叫出来了
Time to get Charlie out. Let's move, Charles.
走了，查尔斯，时间到了
再给我三十秒
Give me another 30 seconds.
你是孩子也要一分十五秒，查理
It takes a minute-fifteen if you're a kid, Charlie...
我上次看你时你还不轻，快走
and, last I looked, you weren't too light on your feet. Now move!
我的天
Oh, my God!
把他们弄出来
Christ! Get 'em out of there!
门锁着的！
The rooms are locked. The rooms are locked!
走，乔
Come on, Joe!
让开！
Out of the way!
把他们弄上屋顶
Help us! Come on!
怎么回事？华特
What's going on, Walter?
建筑物里还有孩子
We still have kids in the building.
我留下来
I'm staying.
不，查理，离开那里
No, Charlie! Get out of there!
你看过亚历山大那个节目吗？
You ever see that show called The Addams Family?
你知道在节目上做什么比赛吗？
They got a motherfucker on there called "Lurch"!
我想我要让你尝尝滋味
You don't think I'm gonna let you get to that gun, do you?
妈的
Fuck!
有四把钥匙
Four! Four!
让开
Fuck it! Get out of the way!
他们在那？华特
Where are they, Walter?
还在里面
Still in.
没有胆子就没有荣耀
No guts, no glory.
我们到屋顶上去还能跳到隔壁幢
If we get to the roof, we can jump to the next building!
狗屎
Oh, shit!
让开
Out of the way!
快！快！快！
Okay, come on.
到上面来，快！
Get 'em up here! Get 'em up here! Come on! Come on!
紧急求救！呼叫海岸防卫队
Mayday! Mayday, Bridgeport Coast Guard. Bridgeport Coast Guard, come in!
快，孩子们
Come on, kids!
狗屎，太宽了
Shit! It's too far!
蹲下来
Over here! Down!
没有胆子就没有荣耀
No guts, no glory.
他们停在港口的中央
It's a big, fucking white fucking boat in the middle of the harbor!
你能等吗？
Please stay on the line.
当然能等
Yeah, sure, I'll stay on the line.
煎饼枫糖浆？
Pancake syrup?
笨！笨！
Stupid! Stupid! Asshole!
哈罗，约翰麦克连
Hello, John McClane.
不是真的有学校炸弹，对吧？
There was never any bomb in the school, was there?
当然没有，我是军人不是怪物
Of course not. I'm a soldier not a monster.
虽然有时候我为怪物工作
Even though I sometimes work for monsters.
真的炸弹在这艘船上
No, the real bomb is on this ship.
海岸防卫队
The Coast Guard.
我告诉他们船在那里
I was tellin' 'em where the boat was.
游戏结束了
Game over, huh?
不尽然
Not quite over.
海岸防卫队，请回答
Bridgeport Coast Guard, come in, please.
他们把你保留在线上？
They put you on hold?
他们要我等
She told me to stay on the line.
天啊！我真喜爱这个国家
Oh, God, I love this country.
你知道你弟弟是个混球吗？
You know, your brother was an asshole.
他真的是
Yeah, he really was an asshole.
他是吗？
He was, he was an asshole.
他真的是，你说对了
You, you got his number. Huh?
好
Yeah, okay.
抱歉，请协助麦克连到下面去
Forgive me. Would you help Mr.McClane below?
小心点
Careful now.
你已经联络了
Now, do you have the communique?
海岸防卫队，请回答
Bridgeport Radio, come in, please. Bridgeport...
海岸防卫队
Coast Guard.
你接了，亲爱的
Are you there, dear?
是的
Yes, we're here.
你是否能记录一项讯息
Do you have the ability to record a message?
行
Yes.
他现在说话了
Then please begin now.
好
All right.
这是CRF的宣言
This is a communique from the CRF.
长久以来西方窃取世界的财富
For too long the West has conspired to steal the wealth of the world...
把维护人道的责任 交给了造成饥荒的经济
consigning the balance of humanity to economic starvation.
今天我们要让大家有同等立足点
Today, we will level the playing field.
几分钟后联邦储备银行的黄金
In a few minutes, the contents of the Federal Reserve Bank...
你们经济的立足点
the gold your economies are built on...
会在爆炸后
will be redistributed by explosive...
粉碎于长岛边的海底
across the bottom of the Long Island Sound.
假如你们有幸，竭诚欢迎观赏
If you are not in gridlock, I invite you to come and watch.
你要把它们全炸掉？
You're gonna blow it all up?
正是那个意思
That's the idea.
中东某位先生认为能从中获暴利
There are some gentlemen in the Middle East...
去看着大家安全的离开
who seem to think that they'll make a great deal of money.
我们在船舷边会合
See the men safely off the ship, and I'll see you in the port-side launch.
那为何要杀麦克连
What the hell's all this got to do with killing McClane?
那是人生的红利
Life has its little bonuses.
你不是说你不喜欢你弟弟？
Didn't I hear you say, you didn't even like your brother?
不喜欢他是一回事
There's a difference,you know,between not liking one's brother
但被个笨爱尔兰人扔出窗户不同
and not caring when some dumb Irish flatfoot drops him out of a window.
我甚至不认识那个王八蛋
Hey, I didn't even know that motherfucker!
我也没有请你到船上来
Yes, but I never invited you aboard this ship.
有什么方法能停止这玩意吗？
No riddle's gonna stop this motherfucker?
没有密码、没有谜语、没有倒数计时
No code, no riddle, no fancy little countdown.
猪头
Hey, fuckhead.
对，就是你，猪头
Yeah, you, fuckhead.
有件事我必须知道
There's just one thing I gotta know.You got any aspirins?
有阿斯匹灵吗？我头痛了一天
I've had a bad fucking headache all day long.
今天是你的幸运日
Must be your lucky day.
整瓶留着吧
Keep the bottle.
黄金在那？
Where is the gold?
他背叛了我们，货柜里全是这个
He's betrayed us. The containers are filled with that!
我若没有救你就不会在这了
If I hadn't have saved your fucking ass, I wouldn't be sittin' here with you...
还有炸弹及值一兆美金的黄金
about to blow up with a hundred billion dollars in fucking gold!
有坏消息，你不会和我一起炸掉
Hey,well,I got some bad news.You're only gonna blow up with me.
什么？
What?
船上没有黄金
There's no gold on this boat.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
我了解那人，我恰好认识他的家人
'Cause I know the man, I know the family.
比炸掉一兆美金黄金更好的方法
The only thing better than blowin' up a hundred billion dollars' worth of gold...
是让别人认为他那么做了
is making people think you did.
那么它会在那？
Yeah? Well, where is it?
应该是在码头调了包
I don't know. He must've switched it back on the docks somewhere.
那应该要让你觉得好过点吗？
Oh, yeah, that's supposed to make me feel better?
不是
No.
你对别的事也错了，你不会死
You're wrong about the other thing, though.You're not gonna die.
你晓得某种警察技俩能松开手铐
Yeah? You know some cop trick about handcuffs that's gonna get us out of this?
是的，有把钥匙
Yeah, use a key.
你会开这种锁吗？
You know how to pick this lock?
这又是黑人的事吗？
Is this some Black shit again?
别来那套种族问题的争论
Now will you stop with that racial shit?
你到底会不会开锁？
Are you a fucking locksmith or not?
我会，假如我有工具的话
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I could do it if I had something to do it with.
我有一节电线芯
How about a splinter of that cable I slid down?
那也许可以
That might work.
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doin'?
妈的
Oh, fuck!
狗屎
Shit!
这个行不行？
How's that? Is that big enough?
也许有用
Shit, yeah. Yeah, that might work.
我吐到你的手上，把手伸过来
All right, I'm gonna drop it in your hands. Cup your hand.
别把它丢掉了，行吗？
Don't drop this motherfucker, all right?
吐好一点
Get it. Get it right. Come on.
行了吗？
You ready?
预备
One...
来吧
Two, spit it.
拿到了吗？
Get it?
快，把你的手移开
Come on, come on. Move your hands.
麦克连，我开始喜欢你了
Okay, okay. Damn, McClane, I was just startin' to like you.
别喜欢我，我是个混球
Yeah? Well, don't. I'm an asshole.
你在说什么？
What are you talkin' about now?
我对你说谎，宙斯
I lied to you, Zeus.
关于什么？
About what?
记得我告诉你炸弹在哈林区找到
You remember I said Weiss found that bomb up in Harlem?
他们是在唐人街找到的
They found it down in Chinatown.
那真低级 就算你是混帐白人也一样
Oh! Oh, now, that's low! Even for a white motherfucker...
所以我说我是混球
I told you I was an asshole.
那是什么？
What the fuck was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是我唯一能让你跟我走的方法
Look, it was the only way I could get you to come with me.
你结婚了吗？麦克连
Uh-huh. You got a wife, McClane?
什么？
Yeah.
竟然有人能够忍受你 还跟你结婚
I'm surprised anybody could stay with you long enough to be married.
是啊，我们在一起也没太久 现在大概是分开了
Yeah, well, she didn't stick around too long. We're sort of separated.
什么叫大概是？
What the fuck is "sort of separated"?
她住洛城我在纽约
Well, she was in L.A., I was in New York.
我们在电话上吵架，她挂断电话
Had a fight on the phone, she hung up.
我没有再打过去
I didn't call her back.
那是多久之前
How long ago was that?
大约是一年前了
About a year ago now.
大约一年…
About a year ago
你在笑什么？
What the fuck are you laughing about?
你真疯了？笨到不会拿起电话来
You threw away your marriage because you were too fucking stupid to pick up the phone?
你认为那很好笑？笑别人的痛苦
What? You think that's funny, huh? You laugh at other people's misfortunes?
你一切都怪罪你太太，对吧？
I bet you blame that shit on your wife too, right?
我太太是个很固执的女人，是的
Well, my wife is a very stubborn woman. Yes.
别笑了，快点解开手铐
Man, you better stop fucking laughing and undo these cuffs!
好了，这样如何？
I'm almost there! There. How's that for concentration?
狗屎
Oh, shit!
怎么啦？
What?
我把那玩意给弄掉了
Fuck! I dropped the thing!
你真是笨
Goddamn it!
东西掉到那里去了？
Shit! Where is it! Where'd it go?
快找到它
Just find it, find it, all right?
我什么都没看见
I don't fucking see it!
那是什么？
What the fuck is that?
我想我让它生气了
I think I made it mad.
快走，麦克连，快离开这
Go, McClane! Get the fuck out of here!
我必须想个办法
Fucking do something!
麦克连，听我说
Goddamn it, McClane! Listen to me!
走就对了
Just go.
我们待在一起一天了都没事
I have a hard enough time getting through the day
我不想良心上愧疚，闭嘴快设法
without having your death on my conscience, man.Shut the fuck up, and think! All right?
好了，工具，轮机室有工具
Okay, okay. Tools, tools. Check the engine room.
没有时间了
There's no time!
它现在在干嘛？
What the hell's it doing now?
在混合
It's mixing.
狗屎
Shit!
你在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
预备好，往前倾
Get ready. Lean forward.
什么？
What?
往前倾
Lean forward!
麦克连
McClane!
现在要爆炸，往前倾
All right, it's gonna go fast! Lean forward!
不！不！不！
What? No, no, no, no!
往前倾
Lean forward!
不做你就会死
Get ready! Move your hands!
妈的
Damn! Motherfuckin' shit! Shit!
快走
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Oh, goddamn! Goddamn!
快点 快点
Come on! Come on!
我的腿
Oh, fuck! My leg!
别站着，快走！快走！
Come on! Go, go,
走！上去
go, go, go! Jump stairs!
狗屎！
Oh, shit!
我们不能停，快走，要爆炸了
Oh, shit! Oh, damn it! Which way? Let's go! Let's go!
跳水
Down here to the back of the boat! Come on!
行吗？
You all right?
快！快！
Yeah.
走！跳下去
Let's go! Down here in the back!
他的情况如何？
How's he doin'?
我腿部中枪，你认为呢？
I got shot in the leg.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be just fine.
你呢？
How about you?
没事，把瑞奇抬出来了吗？
Fine. Did you get Ricky out of there?
他们找到他了
Yeah, they found him.
你不会有事吧？
Are you gonna be all right?
我头痛的要命，他们生我气吗？
Got a bad headache. Think they're mad at me?
我不会去担心他们
I wouldn't worry about them.
最后他们会去找你
They'll get to you eventually,
但现在他们忙着打捞作业
but right now they're busy with this salvage operation,I guess.
不，是卓吉斯
No! Dr-Dredges! Dredges!
他们在浪费时间，下面没有黄金
They're just wasting their time. There's no gold down there.
此话怎讲？
What do you mean?
他带走了，他打败我了
He took it with him. He beat me.
约翰，他打败了我们每一个人
John, he beat all of us.
他不是针对你来的
He wasn't playing against you.
去你的，麦克连，你还活着吧？
Fuck that, McClane! You're still alive, aren't you?
对吧？
Well, aren't you?
所以他输了
Yeah. So we lost.
蓝柏，给他两毛五
Lambert, would you give him a quarter?
混球
Asshole.
是约翰打的对方付费电话
Yeah, it's collect from John.
卡门，告诉她，她会付费的
Yeah, uh, Carmen, just tell them you'll accept the charges.
那王八蛋真的有阿斯匹灵
The son of a bitch had aspirin.
我是约翰，我还好，荷莉在吗？
Yeah, it's John. Yeah, I'm hangin' in there.
等一下
Is Holly there? Yeah, I'll hold on.
宙斯，等一下
Zeus! Hold up! Whoa!
（北方边界）
昨天…
Yesterday...
昨天我们是支没有国家的军队
Yesterday we were an army with no country.
明天我们得决定买那个国家
Tomorrow we have to decide which country we want to buy!
切记，都是因为有你们
And remember...this is all due to the g-g-g-gullibility...
才会有这一切成果
of the New York Police Department!
敬纽约市警局
Police Department!
敬死去的同志
布德曼，你接手
Lieutenant. Take over.
好了，大家听着
All right, listen up!
第一班半小时后搭校车出发
First squad, you muster out in half an hour in the school bus!
飞机在诺瓦史考提亚
我们能在十分钟内离开
不急
No rush.
范洛根
Herr Jurgen,
你当神父
you'll be the padre!
灯光，把灯光灭了
Lights! Douse those lights!
（北方边界）
猪头！
Hey, dick-head!
我来的时机不对吗？
Did I come at a bad time?
我想她生你的气了，麦克连
Whoa! I think she's pissed at you, McClane!
他在我们正下方，转回来
He's under us right now. Come on back around. Come on back around.
- 没错，快逃命吧！- 宙斯，会从你那边出现
- That's right! Run, motherfuckers! - Zeus, what do you got out of your side?
就像蟑螂看到光就都出来了
Look like roaches with the lights comin' on.
要去诺瓦史考提亚吗？
Are we going to Nova Scotia?
你和卡车一起走，我有私事要处理
You go with the trucks. I have something personal to finish.
我们上工去吧
Let's go to work!
没错，逃命吧，把你们了结掉
That's right! Run, motherfuckers! The exterminators are here!
搞什么？
What the hell's going on here?
后面有东西
What the fuck? Oh, shit! Fuck it! There's smoke back here!
有麻烦在我们后面
We got a chopper behind us!
机上有枪吗？
You got a gun on board?
这是什么？
What is this?
他在我们后面
I'm gonna try and get the fuckin' chopper!
稳住，我什么都看不见
I can't see a goddamn thing! Hold it still!
狗屎
Oh, shit!
狗屎什么意思？
What do you mean, "Oh, shit"?
抓稳了，我们要下去了
All right, hang on, hang on! We're going down!
小心电线！电线
See this high tension wire? See this wire?
麦克连，搞什么鬼？
Hey, McClane! What the fuck...
有烟，到处都是烟在熏我
Hey, we got smoke! We got fuckin' smoke and shit flyin' on me here!
卡车！卡车！
Truck! Truck!
稳住，我们下降了
Hold on. Here we go.
走，我们必须离开这
Come on! We gotta get outta here!
他随时会对我们开枪
He's gonna start shootin' at us any second!
我们离开这
Get him outta here!
狗屎
Shit! Shit!
插梢卡住了，我弄不掉它
The belt's stuck! I can't get it off!
小心！他来了
Look out! Here he comes!
我弄不开，麦克连
I can't get out, McClane!
把他弄走
Get him outta here.
你要去那？
Where you goin'?
我试着吸引他的注意
I'm gonna try and get his attention.
狗屎
Shit!
越来越精彩了
Just keeps gettin' better and better.
我想不到加拿大这么好玩
I had no idea Canada could be this much fun.
给我点可以射击的东西，快啊
Just give me something to shoot at. Come on, hotshot.
好让我能扔到他脸上去
Show me that smilin' face.
向你弟弟问好
Say hello to your brother.
快离开这
Get outta here!
再见啦！王八蛋
Yippie-ki-yay, motherfucker.
看起来你吸引到了他的注意力
Looks like you got his attention.
看起来是那样
Yeah, looks like it.
我们该叫消防车
Think we should call a fire truck?
去他的，让他烧吧
Ah, fuck him. Let him cook.
狗屎
Oh, shit!
怎么啦？
What?
我让荷莉在电话上等着
I left Holly hangin' on hold.
再打给她
Aw, call her back.
她会火大的
I don't know. She's gonna be pissed.
会过去的
She'll get over it.
我不知道，宙斯
I don't know, Zeus.
如同我所说的，她很固执
Like I said, she's a very stubborn woman.
可是她凑巧嫁给了你
Yeah, she'd have to be to stay married to you.